<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>
<chapter>
  <title>
    Active Voice
  </title>

  <para>
    Writing in the <firstterm>active voice</firstterm> creates
    powerful and engaging content. The active voice suggests that the
    written word is &#34;speaking&#34; directly to the reader,
    enabling the reader to learn quickly, and to take action an
    exercise requires it. For technical writing, the active voice is
    the clearest way to demonstrate action and
    result, or cause and effect.
  </para>

  <para>
    In the active voice, the subject of the sentence is also
    the person or thing performing an action:
  </para>

  <formalpara>
    <title>Active voice</title>
    <para>
      I compiled the code.
    </para>
  </formalpara>
  
  <para>
    The <firstterm>passive voice</firstterm> is the opposite of active
    voice. In the passive voice, the subject of the sentence is the
    person or thing receiving action:
  </para>

  <formalpara>
    <title>Passive voice</title>
    <para>
      The code was compiled by me.
    </para>
  </formalpara>
    
  <para>
    While the passive voice is not grammatically incorrect, it is less
    efficient than the active voice and also tends to cause confusion
    about who is doing what.
  </para>

  <para>
    For instance, it is impossible for a
    reader to know with certainty whether the sentence &#34;A key
    being pressed prompts the computer to continue,&#34; is an
    instruction to press a key, or just a footnote about what happens
    when a key is pressed.
  </para>

  <para>
    The active voice is both clearer and more concise&#58;
    &#34;Press any key to continue.&#34;
  </para>  

  <section id="active_tutorial">
    <title>How to write in the active voice</title>

    <para>
      Use the active voice by writing as if you're composing a list of
      instructions for your reader. You are not writing a description
      of what the reader would see if the reader were sitting in front
      of your computer, seeing what you see as you write. The reader
      is seeing what is on the screen, and they are doing what you
      tell them to do.
    </para>

    <para>
      Here are some examples of sentences written in the passive
      voice, and how to rewrite them in the active voice&#58;
    </para>

    <variablelist>
      <title>Convert paragraphs to minimalism</title>

      <varlistentry>
	<term>
	  Passive voice&#58;
	</term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    The values of the XML configuration can be found by
	    parsing the file with the Xerces library in C++.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
	<term>
	  Active voice&#58;
	</term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Parse the XML configuration file using the <ulink
	    url="https://xerces.apache.org/xerces-c/">Xerces</ulink>
	    C++ library.
	  </para>
	</listitem>	
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
	<term>
	  Passive voice&#58;
	</term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	     Open XYZ Viewer by double-clicking the XYZ Tools icon from
	     the workstation desktop.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
	<term>
	  Active voice&#58;
	</term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Double-click the <guibutton>XYZ Tools</guibutton> icon on
	    the workstation desktop to open <application>XYZ
	    Viewer</application>.
	  </para>
	</listitem>	
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
	<term>
	  Passive voice&#58;
	</term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    It was presented earlier in this book the syntax for using
	    XML configuration files with a Python module imported into
	    the <application>PyFoo</application> code base.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
	<term>
	  Active voice&#58;
	</term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    The syntax for XML configuration, and the steps to import
	    the required module into 
	    <application>PyFoo</application>, were explained in
	    the <emphasis>Importing the BeautifulSoup module</emphasis>
	    section.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>

    </variablelist>
  </section>

  <section id="active_exercise">
      <title>Exercise</title>

      <para>
	Rewrite each paragraph in the active voice.
      </para>

      <orderedlist>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <!-- Do NOT correct this. It is intentionally wrong. -->
	    The QTextEdit field should be placed in the right corner
	    of the QMainWindow.
	  </para>
	</listitem>

	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <!-- Do NOT correct this. It is intentionally wrong. -->
	    To begin the code compilation process, GCC is used.
	  </para>
	</listitem>

	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <!-- Do NOT correct this. It is intentionally wrong. -->
	    The previous three steps should be repeated to complete
	    RHSM registration on each machine.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </orderedlist>

  </section>
</chapter>
