<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A">
	<title>A</title>
	 <variablelist>
		<varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-amp_and_">
			<term>"&amp;" and "+"</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Ampersands or plus signs can be used in design elements and graphics when space is limited, and when either referring to or quoting third-party content that uses them. Do not use them in original body copy.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-agile_agile_development">
			<term>agile, agile development</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>adj.</emphasis> Use only as an adjective. It is not a proper noun, nor is it owned or trademarked and should not be capitalized.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-air_gap">
			<term>air gap</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>n.</emphasis> Use "air gap" to describe systems that are separated, not by software, but physically. Do not use "air wall." "Air gap" is preferred in technical publications because there is no actual wall that you need to breach, but rather a gap that you need to bridge. You cannot break through something that does not exist.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-a.m._and_p.m.">
			<term>a.m. and p.m.</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. Use the lowercase form and include the periods, and use a preceding space.
				</para>
				 <para>
					See <citetitle>The IBM Style Guide</citetitle> for a full discussion of how to represent times.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-AMD64_and_Intel_64">
			<term>AMD64 and Intel 64</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. Do not use "Hammer," "x86_64," "x86-64," "x64," "64-bit x86" or other variations as the name of this architecture.
				</para>
				 <para>
					The correct term for AMD's implementation of this architecture is "AMD64." The correct term for Intel's implementation of this architecture is "Intel&reg;&nbsp;64." Until late 2006, Intel's official name for the architecture was "Intel EM64T" (for Extended Memory 64 Technology). They have since changed the name to "Intel&reg;&nbsp;64" however, and Red&nbsp;Hat documentation should reflect this change. When discussing the architecture generally, reference both implementations specifically.
				</para>
				 <note>
					<para>
						The AMD64 logo is trademarked; the term "AMD64" is not. For more information about AMD trademarks, see the <citetitle>AMD Trademark Information</citetitle> page at <ulink url="http://www.amd.com/us/aboutamd/Pages/trademarks.aspx" />.
					</para>
					 <para>
						For more information about Intel&reg; trademarks, see <ulink url="http://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/legal/trademarks.html" /> and <ulink url="http://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/trademarks/trademarks.html" />.
					</para>

				</note>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-ATM">
			<term>ATM</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Initialism for Asynchronous Transfer Mode, a network technology based on transferring data in cells or packets of a fixed size. The cell size used with ATM is relatively small compared to units used with older technologies.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-above">
			<term>above</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use to refer to information mentioned previously. When documents are converted to online format, the information may no longer be "above." Use a cross-reference instead.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-acronyms">
			<term>acronyms</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					An acronym is a word formed from the initial letters of a name, such as ROM for <emphasis>R</emphasis>ead <emphasis>O</emphasis>nly <emphasis>M</emphasis>emory, or by combining initial letters or part of a series of words, such as LILO for <emphasis>LI</emphasis>nux <emphasis>LO</emphasis>ader. Note that an acronym is pronounced as a word. Compare this to an initialism, which is also formed in a similar fashion to an acronym, but in which each letter is pronounced separately.
				</para>
				 <para>
					Spell out the acronym or initialism before using it in text, such as "The Embedded DevKit (EDK)..." Unless the acronym or initialism stands for a proper noun, use sentence case for the spelled out version - for example, "central processing unit (CPU)."
				</para>
				 <para>
					To form the plural of an acronym, add a trailing, lowercase "s," or "es," for example, ROMs, PINs, BIOSes.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-alrightall_right">
			<term>alright/all right</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Avoid if at all possible. These terms carry a more familiar or colloquial tone than is expected in Red&nbsp;Hat documentation. Use more formal alternatives such as "correct" or "as expected," depending on context.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-alternate">
			<term>alternate</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use this to mean "an alternative to something." "Alternate" (vb.) means to change between two states or options. If you mean "another way of doing something," use "an alternative method is to..."
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-andor">
			<term>and/or</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Avoid if possible. Try to rewrite to make the available options explicit and clear. Do not write <emphasis>this and/or that</emphasis>. Write <emphasis>this or that or both</emphasis>.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-applications">
			<term>applications</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					When used as a proper name, use the capitalization of the product, such as GNUPro, Source-Navigator, and Red&nbsp;Hat Enterprise&nbsp;Linux. When used as a command, use lowercase as appropriate, such as "To start GCC, type gcc."
				</para>
				 <note>
					<para>
						"vi" is always lowercase.
					</para>

				</note>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-Applixware">
			<term>Applixware</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. Do not use "Applix" or "ApplixWare."
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-as_well_as">
			<term>as well as</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Not interchangeable with "and." "As well as" used in a series places more emphasis on the items preceding it, whereas "and" places equal weight on all items in the series. For example, "We sell kitchen electronics and china, as well as some gourmet foods." But "We sell kitchen electronics, china, and silverware."
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-as_a_Service">
			<term id="aas">as-a-Service</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Be aware that there is a great deal of overlap in as-a-Service acronyms. To avoid confusion, always spell out the full term on first possible use.
				</para>
				 <itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							DRaaS (Disaster Recovery-as-a-Service)
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							CaaS (Cloud-as-a-Service, Communications-as-a-Service, <xref linkend="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-C-Containers_as_a_Service" />)
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							UCaaS (Unified Communications-as-a-Service)
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							FaaS (Function[s]-as-a-Service)
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							SaaS (Search-as-a-Service, Security-as-a-Service, Storage-as-a-Service, or Software-as-a-Service)
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							PaaS (Payments-as-a-Service, Platform-as-a-Service)
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							MaaS (Messaging-as-a-Service)
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							SECaaS (Security-as-a-Service)
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							TDBaaS (Time-series Database as a Service)
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</itemizedlist>
				 <para>
					When using as-a-Service acronyms:
				</para>
				 <itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Capitalize the noun (e.g., Platform, Software, Infrastructure) and Service, both when abbreviated and written out.
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							When in all capitals, such as a title or headline, the aa in the acronym remains lowercase (e.g., INTRODUCTION TO PaaS SOLUTIONS).
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							Hyphenate when written out: Thing-as-a-Service. For two-word prefixes, do not include a hyphen between the first and second words: Mobile Backend-as-a-Service. Can be used as an adjective to describe multiple (e.g., when referring to an IaaS, PaaS, and SaaS, use as-a-Service offerings, as-a-Service products, or similar wording).
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							Avoid an acronym if it could stand for more than one term in a single asset (e.g., if you're writing content that discusses both Cloud-as-a-Service and Containers-as-a-Service).
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</itemizedlist>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-auto_detect">
			<term>auto-detect</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. Do not use "autodetect."
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="varl-The_Red_Hat_Style_Guide-Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors-A-autofs">
			<term>autofs</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Always lowercase. This refers to the kernel-based automount utility. No other forms are recognized.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>

	</variablelist>
</chapter>

