<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="b">
	<title>B</title>
	 <variablelist>
		<varlistentry id="back-end">
			<term>back end, back-end, backend</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>n.</emphasis> Two words. Refers to software that performs the final stages of a process, or to tasks that are not visible to the user. For example, "each back end provides a set of calls".
				</para>
				 <para>
					<emphasis>adj.</emphasis> Hyphenate. For example, "when the back-end database processes a search operation …"
				</para>
				 <para>
					Use "backend", as one word with no hyphen, only if it is part of the established product terminology, for example "Mobile Backend-as-a-Service", and when it is not being used to describe a generic process.
				</para>
				 <para>
					See also <xref linkend="front-end" />
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="back-up">
			<term>backup, back up</term>
			 <listitem>
				 <para>
					Write as one word as an adjective or noun, or as two words as a verb.
				<!-- Depending on usage, this could appear in either of two ways: -->
				</para>
				 <itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis>adj.</emphasis> One word. For example, "store the backup copies of important files in a secure location".
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis>n.</emphasis> One word. For example, "create a backup of your important files".
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis>v.</emphasis> Two words. For example, "always back up important files".
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</itemizedlist>
				 <para>
					Do not use the hyphenated form, "back-up".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="backtrace">
			<term>backtrace</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>n.</emphasis> "Backtrace" is the most common term to refer to a stack trace (or stack backtrace), which is a report of the active stack frames (that is, function calls) at a certain point in time during the execution of a program. In contrast, the Python programming language calls its stack trace a "traceback", possibly because the stack frames are printed in the opposite order of those presented by gdb, the GNU Debugger. "Traceback" is the preferred term when referring to a Python stack trace.
				</para>

			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="backwards-compatible">
			<term>backwards compatible</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use. Instead, use "compatible with earlier versions" to refer to something that is compatible with older equipment or previous versions of software. See also <xref linkend="forwards-compatible" />.
				</para>
<!-- Replaced with "compatible with earlier versions", to align with advice for "forwards-compatible". -->				

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="bandwidth">
			<term>bandwidth</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. Bandwidth can refer to a range within a band of frequencies or wavelengths, or the amount of data that can be transmitted in a fixed time.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="bare-metal">
			<term>bare metal, bare-metal</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>n.</emphasis> Two words.
				</para>
				 <para>
					<emphasis>adj.</emphasis> Hyphenate.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="basically">
			<term>basically</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use. For example, removing the word "basically" in the following sentence strengthens it: "This is how it is basically done." See also <xref linkend="simply" />.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="because-since-as">
			<term>because, since, as</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use "since" or "as" to mean "because"; it is ambiguous. Use "because" to refer to a reason. Use "since" and "as" to indicate the passage of time.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="below">
			<term>below</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use to refer to information that follows later in a document. When documents are converted to online format, the information might no longer be "below". Use a cross-reference instead.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="bimonthly">
			<term>biannual, bimonthly, biweekly, semiweekly, semimonthly</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					People have trouble remembering whether biweekly means "every two weeks" or "twice a week". "Semiweekly" has a similar problem. Even though both terms have clear dictionary definitions, it is best to avoid them in favor of clear communication.
				</para>
				 <para>
					Instead of biweekly, write "every two weeks" or "every other week".
				</para>
				 <para>
					Instead of semiweekly, write "twice a week".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="big-data">
			<term>big data</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>n., adj.</emphasis> Always use lowercase. Do not capitalize except at the beginning of a sentence, or if it is part of a Red&nbsp;Hat product, service, solution, or business unit name. See also <xref linkend="cloud" />. Big data is also never hyphenated, per AP style, even when used as a complex adjective.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="bimodal-it">
			<term>bimodal IT</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Gartner phrase for the combination of traditional (mode 1 or type 1) and modern (mode 2 or type 2) IT infrastructure and resources. Many ways exist to describe this combination approach; be sure to use the right phrase for your audience. Using only the Gartner term can alienate other analysts or those who are not familiar with Gartner's phrasing.
				</para>
				 <para>
					The practice of having both modes together is often referred to as hybrid, agile, or modern IT.
				</para>
				 <note>
					<para>
						Hybrid IT is a more general term, for example it could mean on-premises plus public cloud. Agile and modern IT can both carry an implication of "mode 2", so when using those terms, be specific about the exact technology combination that you mean.
					</para>

				</note>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="bind">
			<term>BIND</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct when referring to the DNS software. Do not use Bind.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="bios">
			<term>BIOS</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. The plural form is BIOSes.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="bit-rate">
			<term>bit rate</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. Do not use "bitrate".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
<!-- Added for inclusive language -->
		 <varlistentry id="blacklist">
			<term>blacklist</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use. Use "denylist" or "blocklist".
				</para>
				<para>
					Do not use the terms "white" or "black" in a context where white is represented as good or black is represented as bad. Such usage reinforces a model that promotes racial bias.
				</para>
			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="boolean">
			<term>Boolean</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. Named after George Boole, who first developed the concept.
				</para>
				 <para>
					According to the <citetitle>IBM Style Guide</citetitle>, it is acceptable to use "boolean" in API programming information when it refers to a primitive return type.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="boot">
			<term>boot</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>v.</emphasis> To load the first piece of software that starts a computer. Because the operating system is essential for running all other programs, it is usually the first piece of software to load during the boot process.
				</para>
				 <para>
					<emphasis>n.</emphasis> Refers to starting up a computer, which involves loading the operating system and other basic software. A cold boot refers to starting a computer that is turned off. A warm boot refers to resetting a computer that is already running.
				</para>
				 <para>
					Boot is an abbreviation of bootstrap, which in olden days was a strap attached to the top of your boot that you could pull to help to get your boot on. Hence, the expression "pull yourself up by the bootstraps". Similarly, bootstrap utilities help the computer to get started.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="boot-disk">
			<term>boot disk</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Two words. Do not use "boot diskette".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="boot-loader">
			<term>boot loader</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Two words. Do not use "bootloader".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="bottleneck">
			<term>bottleneck</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					One word. Do not use "bottle neck" or "bottle-neck".
				</para>
				 <para>
					A bottleneck refers to the delay in transmission of data through the circuits of a computer's microprocessor or over a TCP/IP network. The delay typically occurs when a system's bandwidth cannot support the amount of information that is being relayed at the speed that it is being processed. However, many factors can create a bottleneck in a system.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="bpp">
			<term>bpp</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Initialism for bits per pixel. All letters are lowercase, unless at the beginning of a sentence. Use a non-breaking space between the numeral and the units. For example, "16&nbsp;bpp", not "16bpp".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="bps-bps">
			<term>Bps, bps</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The abbreviation of bytes per second is Bps. The abbreviation of bits per second is bps. To avoid confusion, do not use at the beginning of a sentence. See also <xref linkend="bandwidth" />.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
    <varlistentry id="breadcrumb-trail">
      <term>breadcrumb trail</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          See the <citetitle>IBM Style Guide</citetitle> for initial guidance on how to use this term.
        </para>
        <note>
          <para>
            Do not confuse the breadcrumb trail with the name of the actual page in a user interface. The final breadcrumb in the trail is the name of the page, unless the page itself offers a distinct title. The breadcrumb trail indicates the path that is taken to reach the current page.
          </para>
          <mediaobject id="breadcrumb-trail-example">
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/breadcrumb-trail-example.png" scalefit="1" align="center"/></imageobject>
            <textobject>
              <phrase>
                Example breadcrumb trail, showing <guilabel>Disks</guilabel> as the actual name of the page.
              </phrase>
            </textobject>
            <caption>
                <para>
                  Example breadcrumb trail, showing <guilabel>Disks</guilabel> as the actual name of the page.
                </para>
            </caption>
          </mediaobject>
        </note>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
        <term>break</term>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            (<emphasis>v.</emphasis>) Do not use to mean "break the system" or similar. For example, "applying an unapproved patch might break the system". Choose an alternative such as "cause the system to fail".
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="bring-up">
			<term>bring up</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use. Use "open" instead.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="britain">
			<term>Britain</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					If referring to the language, say "English". If referring to the country, say the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, or the UK. Using Britain or British is usually wrong and might imply a subjective statement about the state of Northern Ireland.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="broadcast">
			<term>broadcast</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					To send the same message simultaneously to multiple recipients. Broadcasting is a useful feature in email systems. 
<!-- Deleted reference to fax. 					
					It is also supported by some fax systems. -->
				</para>
				 <para>
					In networking, a distinction is made between broadcasting and multicasting. Broadcasting sends a message to everyone on the network whereas multicasting sends a message to a selected list of recipients.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="btrfs">
			<term>Btrfs</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					A copy-on-write file system for Linux. Use an uppercase "B" when referring to the file system. When referring to tools, commands, and other utilities that relate to the file system, be faithful to those utilities.
				</para>
				 <para>
					See <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Btrfs" /> for more information on this file system.
				</para>
				 <para>
					See <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_file_systems" /> for a list of file system names and how to present them.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="bug-fix">
			<term>bug fix</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Two words. Do not use "bugfix".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="built-in">
			<term>built-in</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>adj.</emphasis> Hyphenate. Do not use "builtin" unless referring specifically to "Bash builtins" or if it is otherwise a proper noun.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="bunches-of">
			<term>bunches of</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use, unless "bunch" is a specific term that is used in the documented software. Use "many" or some other alternative instead.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="button">
			<term>button</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Describe a UI button as a "button", not a "pushbutton" or "push-button".
				</para>
				 <para>
					Ordinarily you would not include the text "button" in a procedure or description. For example, "Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton> to continue" is perfectly acceptable. It might be necessary to distinguish between buttons and links; for example, "Click the <guibutton>Download</guibutton> link".
				</para>
        <para>
          See also <xref linkend="documenting-ui"/>.
        </para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>

	</variablelist>
</chapter>
