<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="c">
	<title>C</title>
	 <variablelist>
		<varlistentry id="can-may">
			<term>can, may</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Use "can" to describe actions or conditions that are possible. Use "may" only to describe situations where permission is being given. If any of "can", "could", or "may" apply, use "can"; it is less tentative.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="cannot">
			<term>cannot</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct, as one word, when used in the negative form. For example, "you cannot end a sentence with a preposition". Do not use "can not". When used as an additive, use two words. For example, "you can not only end a sentence with a preposition, but you can also start a sentence with a conjunction".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="capex-opex">
			<term>CapEx, OpEx</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. These stand for "capital expenditures" and "operating expenses" respectively. Do not use alternative capitalization.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="cd">
			<term>cd, CD</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					When referring to the change directory command, use <command>cd</command>.
				</para>
				 <para>
					When referring to a compact disk, use "CD". For example, "Insert the CD into the CD drive". The plural is "CDs".
				</para>
				 <para>
					Refer to the Word Usage chapter of the <citetitle>IBM Style Guide</citetitle> for more information.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="CD-1">
			<term>CD #1</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					When referring to a specific CD in the Red&nbsp;Hat Enterprise Linux CD set, it is correct to refer to it as: Red&nbsp;Hat Enterprise Linux CD #1. Avoid using Red&nbsp;Hat Enterprise Linux CD 1.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="ceph">
			<term>Ceph</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. Ceph is a distributed storage platform that provides object, block, and file storage.<footnote> <para>
						Refer to <ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ceph_%28software%29" />
					</para>
					 </footnote> Do not use alternative capitalization.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="cgroup">
			<term>cgroup</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct (all lowercase) when referring to the kernel-based technology. It is a contraction of control group, and not a proper noun in itself; proper nouns use initial caps. It is therefore permissible to capitalize it if used at the beginning of a sentence.
				</para>
				 <para>
					Where cgroup refers to something else, for example, a package name, file name, and so on, use a literal rendition.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="characters">
			<term>characters</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use "characters" to mean "bytes". In English, bytes and characters can be used interchangeably; in other languages, a single character might consist of multiple bytes.
				</para>
				 <para>
					In computer software, a character is a symbol, such as a letter or number, that represents information. This includes all the ASCII and extended ASCII characters, including the space character. In character-based software, everything that appears on the screen, including graphics symbols, is considered to be a character. In graphics-based applications, the term character is generally reserved for letters, numbers, and punctuation.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="chip-set">
			<term>chipset</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>n.</emphasis> One word. Do not use "chip set" or "chip-set".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="cicd">
			<term>CI/CD</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Define on first use; generally continuous integration/continuous delivery. It does not mean continuous development, a term with questionable usefulness and only marginal adoption.
				</para>
				 <para>
					Refer also to <xref linkend="continuous-integration" />, <xref linkend="continuous-delivery" />, <xref linkend="continuous-deployment" />.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="ciphertext">
			<term>ciphertext</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>n.</emphasis> One word. Do not use "cipher text", "cipher-text", or other variants.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="click">
			<term>click</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>v.</emphasis> Use when referring to a UI control button, for example, "Click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>." Do not use "click on".
				</para>
<!-- Added comment about "click on". -->
				 <para>
					Refer to the Word Usage chapter of the <citetitle>IBM Style Guide</citetitle> for more information.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="client-side">
			<term>client-side, client side</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>adj.</emphasis> Use the hyphenated form as an adjective. For example: "Winbind is a client-side service to connect to some Windows servers."
				</para>
				 <para>
					<emphasis>n.</emphasis> Use the two-word form as a noun. For example: "Winbind runs on the client side of a client/server Samba implementation."
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="clobber">
			<term>clobber, clobbered</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Avoid these and similar terms unless they are the actual name of something. Use "altered", "invalidated", or "overwritten", or whatever is appropriate in the context.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="cloud">
			<term>cloud</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Although cloud is important to Red&nbsp;Hat's business, it is not a proper noun. Do not capitalize, unless it is part of a Red&nbsp;Hat product, service, solution, or business unit name. Use a lowercase "c" when referring to cloud or cloud computing in a general sense. Use a capitalized "C" when referring to the full name of official products, such as Red&nbsp;Hat CloudForms or Red&nbsp;Hat Cloud Foundations. Refer also to "big data".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="cloudbursting">
			<term>cloudbursting</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Define briefly on first use.
				</para>
				 <para>
					Refers to the event where a private cloud exceeds its capacity and "bursts" into and uses public cloud resources. The advantage of such a hybrid cloud deployment is that an organization pays only for extra computing resources when they are needed.<footnote> <para>
						<ulink url="http://searchcloudcomputing.techtarget.com/definition/cloud-bursting" />
					</para>
					 </footnote>
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="cloudwashing">
			<term>cloudwashing</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Define briefly on first use.
				</para>
				 <para>
					Refers to the process of rebranding legacy products to include the term "cloud" to increase their appeal to the cloud market, even if such inclusion is not completely justified.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="code">
			<term>code</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>n.</emphasis> Use only as a noun, not a verb. Use "write" for a verb.
				</para>
<!-- Is this restriction still in force, even though Merriam-Webster allows "code" as a verb? What about "coding"? -->				

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
<!-- Added "colocate, colocation" -->
		 <varlistentry id="colocate">
			<term>colocate, colocation</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Write unhyphenated, to refer to people or services in the same location.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="combo-box">
			<term>combo-box</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use as an abbreviation for "combination box". Refer to the relevant entry in the <citetitle>IBM Style Guide</citetitle> for further usage information.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="comma-delimited">
			<term>comma-delimited</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>adj.</emphasis> Correct (compound adjective). A data format in which each piece of data is separated by a comma. This is a popular format for transferring data from one application to another, because most database systems are able to import and export comma-delimited data.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="csv">
			<term>comma-separated values (CSV)</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Use this in preference to "comma-delimited values" whenever possible. The initialism CSV is widely used to denote information that is broken up through use of commas. This method is often used to share data between different, but similar applications, wherein the comma is a translator of the data.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="command-button">
			<term>command button</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Use "button" instead.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="command-driven">
			<term>command-driven</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>adj.</emphasis> Correct (compound adjective). Do not use "command driven" or "commanddriven".
				</para>
				 <para>
					Refers to programs and operating systems that accept commands in the form of special words or letters. In contrast, programs that provide a list of options in a menu are said to be <emphasis>menu-driven</emphasis>.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="command-language">
			<term>command language</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>n.</emphasis> The programming language through which a user communicates with the operating system or an application. For example, the DOS command language includes the commands DIR, COPY, and DEL, to name a few. The part of an operating system that responds to operating system commands is called the <emphasis>command processor</emphasis>.
				</para>
				 <para>
					With graphical user interfaces, the command language consists of operations that you perform with a mouse or similar input device.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="command-line">
			<term>command line, command prompt, command-line</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Refer to the appropriate entries in the <citetitle>IBM Style Guide</citetitle> for an explanation of how to use these terms.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="commodity">
			<term>commodity</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Avoid using "commodity" when referring to hardware, including servers or storage, because it implies that the hardware is undifferentiated and might imply that it is cheap. Use instead:
				</para>
				 <itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Volume
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							Industry-standard
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</itemizedlist>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="csp">
			<term>communication service provider (CSP)</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Another way to refer to a telecommunications provider. Refer also to <xref linkend="telco" />.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="containers-as-a-service">
			<term>Containers-as-a-Service</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The term "Containers-as-a-Service" is owned by Docker and should be used only when referring to that company's offering. Refer also to <xref linkend="as-a-service" />.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="container-based">
			<term>container-based</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Used to refer to more complex applications with multiple services that are distributed in containers. More common than "containerized".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="containerized">
			<term>containerized</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Used to refer to an application or service that is distributed in a container or packed in a container.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="continuous-delivery">
			<term>continuous delivery (CD)</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					A software implementation architecture that ensures that all approved code can be easily pushed to production.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="continuous-deployment">
			<term>continuous deployment</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					A special case of continuous delivery, where approved code is automatically pushed to production. Do not use "CD" to refer to this practice.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="continuous-integration">
			<term>continuous integration (CI)</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					A software development architecture where the developer code branch is synchronized with the main code branch multiple times per day. Development always works with the current code base.
				</para>
<!-- Deleted "or master". -->				

			</listitem>

<!-- Moved "contractions" (not a named term) to Chapter 2. -->
		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="control-character">
			<term>control character</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					A special, non-printing character that begins, modifies, or ends a function, event, operation, or control operation. The ASCII character set defines 32 control characters. Originally, these codes were designed to control teletype machines. Now, however, they are often used to control display monitors, printers, and other modern devices.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="control-key">
			<term>control key</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Use <keycap>Ctrl</keycap> instead, such as "To save the program, press <keycombo><keycap>Ctrl</keycap><keycap>S</keycap></keycombo>."
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="control-program">
			<term>control program</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					A program that enhances an operating system by creating an environment in which you can run other programs. Control programs generally provide a graphical interface and enable you to run several programs at once in different windows.
				</para>
				 <para>
					Control programs are also called <emphasis>operating environments</emphasis>.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 
		 <varlistentry id="cookie">
			<term>cookie</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>n.</emphasis> Data that is given to a web browser by a web server.
          The browser stores the message in a text file that might be named <filename>cookie.txt</filename>.
          The message is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 
		 <varlistentry id="cr">
			<term>CR</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Use if referring to code, such as "Type CR at the end of each line ...". If referring to the keyboard key, use either <keycap>Enter</keycap> or <keycap>Return</keycap>, depending on the platform.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="crash">
			<term>crash</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					IBM recommends the use of "fail" rather than "crash". Use the latter only if you can justify why "fail" is inadequate.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="cross-platform">
			<term>cross-platform</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>adj.</emphasis> Hyphenate. Do not use "crossplatform" or "cross platform".
				</para>
				 <para>
					Refers to the capability of software or hardware to run identically on different platforms.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="cross-site-scripting">
			<term>cross-site scripting</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. When referring to cross-site scripting attacks, use "cross-site scripting attack". Acceptable use is also "cross-site scripting (XSS) attack".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
    <varlistentry id="cve">
      <term>CVE</term>
      <listitem>
        <para>
          <emphasis>n.</emphasis> CVE stands for Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures, and should be capitalized as shown.
          Refer to <ulink url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Common_Vulnerabilities_and_Exposures"></ulink> for more information.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="cygmon">
			<term>Cygmon</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. Do not use "CygMon", "cygmon", or "CYGMON". An exception is if a command is being typed (such as <command>cygmon</command>).
				</para>
				 <para>
					Refer to it as "Cygmon: a ROM monitor", not "Cygmon: the Cygnus ROM monitor", or "Cygmon: the ROM monitor".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>

	</variablelist>
</chapter>

