<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="design">
	<title>Design</title>
	 <xi:include href="Book_Design.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	 <section id="heading-styles">
		<title>Heading Styles</title>
    <para>
      This section covers various aspects of heading styles and design.
      If your company or organisation has specific requirements in this regard, follow those requirements first.
    </para>
		 <formalpara id="capitalization">
				<title>Capitalization</title>
					<para>
						The standard for all Red&nbsp;Hat technical documentation is title case for all headings and titles.
            Diagram labels, table headings, procedure, and formal paragraph titles all fall under this heading, and consequently, standard title case capitalization rules apply.
            The currently accepted reference for determining title case is <ulink url="http://titlecase.com">http://titlecase.com.</ulink>
					</para>
          </formalpara>
					 <para>
						Use sentence case for table column headers.
            These are not classified as titles.
					</para>
					 <warning>
						<title>Marketing and Brand Capitalization Guide</title>
						 <para>
							The Red&nbsp;Hat Marketing and Brand groups use sentence case for most titles and headings, with some exceptions, for example, when referencing an externally produced resource's title.
						</para>

					</warning>

      <formalpara>
        <title>Punctuation</title>

          <para>
            Be frugal with punctuation.
            In most cases, avoid semicolons, colons, dashes, and similar punctuation unless part of the actual subject, or a proper name.
            Do not use terminating periods.
            </para>
          </formalpara>
			 <formalpara id="imperative-form">
				<title>Avoid Imperative Form</title>
					<para>
						Use the gerund form (noun form of verb) for titles, not the imperative form.
					</para>
          </formalpara>
					 <para>
						See <citetitle>The IBM Style Guide</citetitle> for more information.
					</para>
					 <important>
						<para>
							Gerunds should be avoided elsewhere.
              Refer to <xref linkend="sentence-structure" />.
						</para>
					</important>
      <formalpara>
        <title>File Names, Commands, and Related Terms</title>
          <para>
            When creating chapter and section titles, do not include file, command, or similar names, and do not include DocBook elements.
            Instead, focus on the task at hand and introduce the required file and command names in the text.
            Including such objects in titles is generally considered poor technical writing practice.
            Depending on how your documentation is built and delivered, including these object types can result in unpredictable results and even cause failed builds.
          </para>
		</formalpara>

	</section>
	 <section id="documenting-fonts">
		<title>Documenting Fonts</title>
		 <para>
			The preferred way to refer to each type of postscript font is "PostScript Type x," substituting "x" with either 1, 2, or 3, if the problem is specific to a particular type.
		</para>

	</section>
	 <section id="documenting-ui">
		<title>Documenting the User Interface</title>
		 <para>
			In all cases, see <citetitle>The IBM Style Guide</citetitle> for initial guidance.
      The following sections highlight exceptions or cases that might otherwise cause confusion.
		</para>
		 <section id="gui-elements-punctuation">
			<title>GUI Elements and Punctuation</title>
			 <para>
				Do not include punctuation that appears on GUI elements, unless omission of that punctuation might lead to confusion.
			</para>
			 <para>
				For example, for a button labeled <guibutton>Save As...</guibutton>, do not include the ellipsis in the documentation.
			</para>
			 <para>
				See the <citetitle>Computer Interfaces</citetitle> chapter in <citetitle>The IBM Style Guide</citetitle> for more information.
			</para>

		</section>
		 <section id="starting-apps">
			<title>Starting Applications from the Red&nbsp;Hat Enterprise&nbsp;Linux Desktop</title>
			 <para>
				Red&nbsp;Hat Enterprise&nbsp;Linux&nbsp;7 introduces a new approach to starting applications from the desktop. In an effort to maintain consistency and to make translation easier, Red&nbsp;Hat documentation assumes the customer is using GNOME Classic, the default user interface, and prefers a consistent approach to instructing customers how to start applications.
			</para>
			 <para>
				The preferred approach is to use the <keycap>Super</keycap> key to enter the Activities Overview, enter the name of the required application, and to press <keycap>Enter</keycap>. The <keycap>Super</keycap> key appears in a variety of guises, depending on the keyboard and other hardware, but often as either the <keysym>Windows</keysym> or <keysym>Command</keysym> key, and typically to the left of the <keycap>Spacebar</keycap>. For example:
			</para>
			 <example id="exam-starting-apps">
				<title>Preferred Approach to Starting Applications from the Desktop</title>
				 <para>
					To start <command>gedit</command>, press the <keycap>Super</keycap> key to enter the Activities Overview, type <literal>gedit</literal>, and then press <keycap>Enter</keycap>.
				</para>

			</example>

		</section>
		 <section id="documenting-command-syntax">
			<title>Documenting Command Syntax</title>
			 <para>
				See the <citetitle>Computer Interfaces</citetitle> chapter of <citetitle>The IBM Style Guide</citetitle> for initial guidance. The following examples are intended to highlight correct usage.
			</para>
			 <example id="exam-documenting-command-syntax">
				<title>Cloning a Git Repository</title>
				 <para>

<screen>$ git clone <replaceable>[username@]hostname:/repository_filename [directory]</replaceable></screen>

				</para>

			</example>
			 <para>
				In <xref linkend="exam-documenting-command-syntax" /> the entire command consists of the following components:
			</para>
			 <variablelist>
				<varlistentry id="command-syntax-prompt">
					<term>The prompt (<prompt>$</prompt>)</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							Indicates that a normal user can run the command, as compared to the <systemitem>root</systemitem> user, indicated by the number sign (<prompt>#</prompt>).
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry id="command-git-clone">
					<term>The command (<command>git clone</command>)</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							The actual command to run, without any optional or replaceable values. This must be typed as is.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry id="source-options">
					<term>Source options <replaceable>[username@]hostname:/repository_filename</replaceable>)</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							The optional user name, indicated by brackets ([]), followed by the host name and path to the repository. All aspects of this component must be replaced with valid values.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry id="target-options">
					<term>Target options <replaceable>[directory]</replaceable></term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							The optional directory into which the repository will be cloned. This must be replaced with a valid value, or omitted.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>

			</variablelist>
			 <example id="exam-secure-copy">
				<title>Securely Copying a File Between Hosts</title>

<screen>$ scp <replaceable>filename [username@]hostname:/directory</replaceable></screen>

			</example>
			 <para>
				In <xref linkend="exam-secure-copy" /> the entire command consists of the following components:
			</para>
			 <variablelist>
				<varlistentry id="command-prompt">
					<term>The command prompt (<prompt>$</prompt>)</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							Indicates that a normal user can run the command, as compared to the <systemitem>root</systemitem> user, which is indicated by the number sign (<prompt>#</prompt>).
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry id="command-scp">
					<term>The command (<command>scp</command>)</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							The actual command to run, without any optional or replaceable values. This must be typed as is.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry id="command-syntax-source-filename">
					<term>Source options (<replaceable>filename</replaceable>)</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							The file name to copy. This must be replaced with a valid value.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>
				 <varlistentry>
					<term>Target options (<replaceable>[username@]hostname:/directory</replaceable>)</term>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							The optional user name, indicated by brackets ([]), followed by the host name and path to the target directory. All aspects of this component must be replaced with valid values.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</varlistentry>

			</variablelist>
			 <warning>
				<para>
					Avoid using the <option>--force (-f)</option> and <option>--assumeyes (-y)</option> options on most commands, especially when logged in as the <systemitem>root</systemitem> user. This can lead to unintended consequences, such as removing files or directories by mistake or installing packages or other software that may not suit your system. Refer to the following examples:
				</para>

<screen>[root@serverc pam.d]# rm -f system-auth password-auth (omit the -f)
[root@serverc ~]# yum install -y new-package (omit the -y)
</screen>
				 <para>
					In some cases, such as in Ansible Playbooks or other automation scripts, it may be necessary to use these options.
				</para>

			</warning>
			 <section>
				<title>Documenting Multiple or Long Commands</title>
				 <para>
					Sometimes you need to demonstrate how to use very long commands that extend over two or more lines, or include several commands in a single example. If the commands are relatively short and straightforward, include the commands on consecutive lines:
				</para>
				 <example>
					<title>Documenting Multiple Commands</title>

<screen>$ cd Documents
$ vi myFile.txt
</screen>

				</example>
				 <para>
					If the commands are long, complex, or wrap over multiple lines, use the following design to help optimize clarity, and to make it easy for users to copy and paste the command if required:
				</para>
				 <example>
					<title>Documenting Long Commands</title>

<screen># tar --selinux -czvf config_files.tar.gz  /etc/katello \
/etc/elasticsearch /etc/candlepin /etc/pulp /etc/gofer \
/etc/grinder /etc/pki/katello /etc/pki/pulp /etc/qpidd.conf \
/etc/sysconfig/katello /etc/sysconfig/elasticsearch \
/root/ssl–build /var/www/html/pub/* /var/lib/katello

# cd /var/lib/katello

# myCommand --option funky --color=true \
--config_file=&lt;replaceable&gt;/home/user/config.conf&lt;/replaceable&gt; \
--output_file=&lt;replaceable&gt;/home/user/output.txt&lt;/replaceable&gt;</screen>

				</example>

			</section>
      <section id="replaceable-paths">
        <title>Referring to Replaceable Paths</title>
          <para>
            To refer to a path that users need to replace with something specific to their system, use &lt;replaceable&gt; tags, the correct syntax for the system and object in question, and an indicative name.
            Use a leading slash if the absolute path is required.
          </para>
          <example><title>Referring to Replaceable Paths on Linux Systems</title>
            <para>
              "Mount the ISO file in &lt;filename&gt;&lt;replaceable&gt;/path/to/iso/file&lt;/replaceable&gt;&lt;/filename&gt;."
            </para>
          </example>
          <para>
            Remember to use the syntax appropriate to the system that you are documenting or describing.
          </para>
          <example><title>Referring to Replaceable Paths on Microsoft Windows Systems</title>

          <para>
            "Mount the ISO file in &lt;filename&gt;&lt;replaceable&gt;C:\path\to\iso\file&lt;/replaceable&gt;&lt;/filename&gt;."
          </para>
          </example>
          <para>
            If you are referring to a different object class or type with different delimiters, use the appropriate delimiters.
            For example:
          </para>
          <para>
            A PATH variable for Bash might appear as &lt;replaceable&gt;/usr/bin:/usr/local/bin&lt;/replaceable&gt;.
          </para>
          <para>
            A package path in Lua might appear as &lt;replaceable&gt;local.share.lua&lt;/replaceable&gt;.
          </para>
        </section>

		</section>
		 <section id="view-edit-files">
			<title>Describing How to View and Edit Files</title>
			 <para>
				To describe how to view and edit files, such as configuration files, scripts, and so on, do not include editor names as part of the guidance, unless the topic is about a specific editor, or is otherwise necessary to achieve a desired result.
			</para>
			 <para>
				For example, do not refer to <command>cat</command> or <command>vi</command> if you need to tell readers to "View the <filename>my-script</filename> file." If you need to tell readers to edit a file and add or remove content, write "Edit the <filename>my-script</filename> file and add the following content:" and then include the required content in a &lt;screen&gt; block. Use &lt;code&gt; tags to highlight the text that needs to be changed. Include some surrounding text in the file for context. Do not use line numbers as a reference point because they can change.
			</para>
			 <para>
				If the file that you need to edit is empty or does not exist, do not use &lt;code&gt; tags to highlight any content that needs to be added.
			</para>
			 <para>
				You can also use <systemitem>here</systemitem> documents to describe how to create a file with required content. The syntax of <systemitem>here</systemitem> documents varies by system, shell, language, and so on, but a simple example is shown below. This example creates the <filename>my-script</filename> file in the current directory, using the example content.
			</para>

<screen><![CDATA[$ cat << EOF > my-script
> # The first line of text
> # The second line
> # Start adding variables after this line
> EOF]]></screen>
			 <para>
				In some cases it is necessary to indicate which tool to use to view a file. This is especially true of log files and other very long files. In these cases, suggest a viewer based on the operating system or environment in which you are working, such as <command>tail</command>, <command>head</command>, <command>less</command>, or <command>journalctl</command>.
			</para>

		</section>
		 <section id="use-hostnames-correctly">
			<title>Using Host and User Names Correctly</title>
			 <para>
				Many examples in Red&nbsp;Hat documentation require the use of user names, host names, IP addresses, and similar information. In an effort to reduce security risks, to minimize translation overhead, and to maintain consistency, Red&nbsp;Hat recommends the following.
			</para>
			 <note>
				<para>
					All names are lowercase. Do not use white space in any part of the name.
				</para>

			</note>
			 <itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use <ulink url="http://tools.ietf.org/search/rfc2606">RFC 2606</ulink> to determine suitable domain names. For documentation and example purposes, this is typically <systemitem>example.com</systemitem>, <systemitem>example.net</systemitem>, <systemitem>example.org</systemitem>, and <systemitem>example.edu</systemitem>.
					</para>
					 <important>
						<para>
							Do not use valid, public IP addresses in any examples.
						</para>

					</important>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						As much as possible, use <systemitem>user</systemitem>, <systemitem>username</systemitem>, <systemitem>root</systemitem>, <systemitem>admin</systemitem>, or similar names to identify classes of users.
					</para>
					 <para>
						Use these generic names when you refer to users outside of a case study. This helps students identify which part of a command can and should be replaced by establishing a consistent format for names of users and system items. For example:
					</para>

<screen><prompt>[root@fedora ~]# </prompt><userinput>setfacl -m u:user1:rw /project/file1</userinput></screen>
					 <para>
						The following list provides further alternatives:
					</para>
					 <itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								<systemitem>operator1</systemitem> to <systemitem>operator9</systemitem>
							</para>

						</listitem>
						 <listitem>
							<para>
								<systemitem>developer1</systemitem> to <systemitem>developer9</systemitem>
							</para>

						</listitem>
						 <listitem>
							<para>
								<systemitem>architect1</systemitem> to <systemitem>architect9</systemitem>
							</para>

						</listitem>

					</itemizedlist>

				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>
			 <section id="using-extended-names">
				<title>Using Extended User and Group Names</title>
				 <para>
					Sometimes, the recommended list of user and group names is too restrictive for the scope of a book or article. In such cases, the following extended model is acceptable.
				</para>
				 <formalpara id="using-realistic-names">
					<title>Using Realistic User Names</title>
					 <para>
						When you are writing a detailed case study, such as training exercises, reviews, and similar material, use realistic names. These names should not be real people. In other words, do not use the name of an employee, a well-known person, or your neighbor.
					</para>

				</formalpara>
				 <para>
					For example, you are the system administrator at Global Banking and you have been asked to set up permissions to the accounting directory for the following users: John Doe, Sunni Koning, Huong Sabo, and Jerlene Paluch. John is a department manager and needs to be able to read from the accounting directory, Sunni is the lead accountant and needs both read and write access.
				</para>
				 <formalpara id="choosing-realistic-names">
					<title>Choosing a Realistic Name</title>
					 <para>
						Consider the following when choosing a realistic name: <footnote> <para>
							Examples taken from <citetitle>The IBM Style Guide</citetitle> and the <citetitle>Google Developer Documentation Style Guide</citetitle>.
						</para>
						 </footnote>
					</para>

				</formalpara>
				 <itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							In examples or scenarios, you can use a person's name and then use a gender-specific pronoun to refer to that name. Vary the use of proper names in documentation. Use names that represent various ethnic backgrounds, genders, and locations.
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							Do not use copyrighted fictional characters in examples, and do not use real people.
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							Include a diverse set of names in your examples to reflect the diversity of the real world. For example, use male, female, and culturally diverse names that suggest a variety of backgrounds in examples to avoid implying that only certain groups have specific skills.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</itemizedlist>
				 <formalpara id="sourcing-realistic-names">
					<title>Sourcing Realistic Names</title>
					 <para>
						You can use any of the following name generators to create realistic names for users:
					</para>

				</formalpara>
				 <itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<ulink url="https://uinames.com/">https://uinames.com/</ulink>
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							<ulink url="http://listofrandomnames.com/">http://listofrandomnames.com/</ulink>
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							<ulink url="http://www.behindthename.com/random/">http://www.behindthename.com/random/</ulink>
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							<ulink url="http://random-name-generator.info/">http://random-name-generator.info/</ulink>
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</itemizedlist>
				 <formalpara id="using-extended-group-names">
					<title>Group Names</title>
					 <para>
						Use any lowercase name that is a logical extension of the accepted user names, without the numerical suffix. For example, <systemitem>architects</systemitem>, <systemitem>developers</systemitem>, <systemitem>operators</systemitem>.
					</para>

				</formalpara>

			</section>

		</section>

	</section>
	 <section id="document-currencies">
		<title>Documenting Currencies</title>
		 <para>
			Use local currency symbols wherever possible. If symbol clash occurs (USD vs AUD, for example), disambiguate with the 2-character country code. For example, US$, AU$.
		</para>
		 <important>
			<para>
				Do not provide currency conversions.
			</para>

		</important>

	</section>
	 <section id="using-abbreviations">
		<title>Using Abbreviations, Acronyms, and Initialisms Correctly</title>
		 <para>
			This section describes how to use abbreviations, acronyms, and initialisms correctly in Red&nbsp;Hat documentation.
		</para>
		 <formalpara>
			<title>Abbreviations</title>
			 <para>
				An abbreviation is a shortened form of a word or phrase. For example, <abbrev>Pty.</abbrev> and <abbrev>Inc.</abbrev> are abbreviations for "proprietary" and "incorporated," respectively. Read them as the word for which they are an abbreviation.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <formalpara id="using-acronyms">
			<title>Acronyms</title>
			 <para>
				What are acronyms anyway? They are similar to abbreviations and initialisms but they are pronounced as an actual word. For example, <acronym>COBOL</acronym> is the acronym for Common Business-oriented Language, and <acronym>POP</acronym> is the acronym for Post Office Protocol.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <para>
			Bear pronunciation in mind when using articles. For example, use "an <abbrev>RTS</abbrev> (real-time strategy)," because <abbrev>RTS</abbrev> is an initialism and you pronounce the first character as an "R" (är). Conversely, use "a <acronym>RAM</acronym> upgrade," because <acronym>RAM</acronym> is an acronym and you pronounce it as a word (răm).
		</para>
		 <para>
			Be sure to use correct capitalization for acronyms. Not all acronyms are capitalized (for example, "spool"); see <citetitle>The IBM Style Guide</citetitle> or another suitable reference if you are unsure.
		</para>
		 <formalpara>
			<title>Initialisms</title>
			 <para>
				An initialism is an abbreviation that consists of the first letters of words in a phrase, syllables, or some combination thereof. Each character is pronounced separately. For example, <abbrev>FTP</abbrev> is an initialism for <systemitem class="protocol">File Transfer Protocol.</systemitem>
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <para>
			Bear pronunciation in mind when using articles. See <xref linkend="acronyms" /> for more information.
		</para>

	</section>
	 <section id="product-names">
		<title>Using Company, Product, and Brand Names Correctly</title>
		 <para>
			A number of restrictions apply to using company, product, and brand names in Red&nbsp;Hat documentation. Refer to internal sources for further conditions that might apply to your own products.
		</para>
		 <note>
			<para>
				In the following sections, "first use" refers to the first use of a name in body text. Titles, banners, and similar objects are not classified as "first use."
			</para>

		</note>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Restrictions apply to abbreviating Red&nbsp;Hat product or solution names in public-facing documents. Always use the full name on first use. For some products, for example Red&nbsp;Hat OpenShift Container Platform, you can omit "Red&nbsp;Hat" after the first use.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Further restrictions apply to using acronyms and initialisms. In this same example, and only in technical documentation, "RHOCP" is acceptable after the first use of the full product name.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not include "Inc." when referring to Red&nbsp;Hat except in legal documents.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Use non-breaking spaces to avoid breaking the company name over multiple lines. This also applies to product names and their versions. For example, use a non-breaking space between "Red" and "Hat," and also between "Enterprise," "Linux," and the version number.
				</para>
				 <para>
					If you are working with images or other objects where space is especially tight, this rule is more flexible, but "Red&nbsp;Hat" should never be broken over two lines.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use non-breaking spaces between "Red&nbsp;Hat" and any product name. Consider the following examples:
				</para>
				 <itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Standardize on Red&amp;nbsp;Hat Enterprise&amp;nbsp;Linux.
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							The latest version is Red&amp;nbsp;Hat Enterprise&amp;nbsp;Linux&amp;nbsp;7.0
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</itemizedlist>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use non-breaking spaces between extended components of Red&nbsp;Hat product names. For example, "Red&nbsp;Hat Enterprise&nbsp;Linux OpenStack Platform" does not require a non-breaking space between "Linux" and "OpenStack" nor between "OpenStack" and "Platform."
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use non-breaking spaces with other companies' product names.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use articles in front of product names. For example, do not write "the JBoss Enterprise&nbsp;Application&nbsp;Platform was..."
				</para>
				 <note>
					<para>
						In this case, "Platform" is part of the product name. In other cases, words like "platform," "manager," and so on may not be part of the product name, in which case an article is acceptable, if not necessary.
					</para>

				</note>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>

	</section>
	 <section id="version-numbers">
		<title>Using Version Numbers Correctly</title>
		 <para>
			The preferred format for product names includes only the major version number. For example:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Red&nbsp;Hat Enterprise&nbsp;Linux&nbsp;7
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						JBoss Enterprise&nbsp;Application&nbsp;Platform&nbsp;3
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>

		</para>
		 <para>
			When writing about a product line, product release, or product family, use major version numbers. This includes all the releases (past, present, and future) of that major version.
		</para>
		 <para>
			Only use minor version numbers when you are referring to a specific minor release, or to a feature that is specific to that minor release. For example:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Red&nbsp;Hat Enterprise&nbsp;Linux&nbsp;5.2 was released on October 12, 2010.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						&lt;Application name&gt; was first included in JBoss Enterprise&nbsp;Application&nbsp;Platform&nbsp;3.2.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>

		</para>
		 <para>
			In most cases, major changes take place in major version releases, and are carried through any minor updates to that release. If you are referring to a major change, or to the first appearance of a new technology, it is therefore most accurate to refer to the major release.
		</para>
		 <para>
			Avoid using the "dot-oh" release number. For example, do not use Red&nbsp;Hat Enterprise&nbsp;Linux&nbsp;6.0. Use instead Red&nbsp;Hat Enterprise&nbsp;Linux&nbsp;6.
		</para>
		 <important>
			<para>
				This rule only applies to Red&nbsp;Hat products. Refer to other companies' products and use their version numbers as they use them.
			</para>

		</important>

	</section>
	 <section id="admonitions">
		<title>Using Admonitions</title>
		 <para>
			To call attention to a statement, use an admonition. Red&nbsp;Hat technical documentation currently uses <command>Note</command>, <command>Important</command>, and <command>Warning</command> admonitions.
		</para>
		 <para>
			Admonitions automatically include a suitable title according to the type of admonition. Do not use a phrase or anything else for the title. Keep the following in mind if using admonitions:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Keep the statements as brief and to the point as possible.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Use admonitions sparingly so that they do not lose their effectiveness.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Use a <command>Note</command> admonition to bring additional information to the user's attention.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Use an <command>Important</command> admonition to show the user a piece of information that should not be overlooked. While this information may not change anything the user is doing, it should show the user that this piece of information could be vital.
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Use a <command>Warning</command> admonition to alert the reader that the current setup will change or be altered, such as files being removed, and not to perform the operation unless fully aware of the consequences.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>

		</para>

	</section>
	 <section id="citing-other-works">
		<title>Citing Other Works</title>
		 <formalpara id="other-books">
			<title>Referencing Other Books</title>
			 <para>
				When referencing another book, either internal or external to Red&nbsp;Hat, use the following format:
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <para>
			In XML:
		</para>

<programlisting>
&lt;citetitle&gt;Book Title&lt;/citetitle&gt; by &lt;author&gt;&lt;firstname&gt;First name&lt;/firstname&gt;&lt;surname&gt;Surname&lt;/surname&gt;&lt;/author&gt;; Publisher.
</programlisting>
		 <para>
			For example, <citetitle>Maximum RPM</citetitle> by
			<author>
				<firstname>Edward</firstname>
				 <surname>Bailey</surname>

			</author>
			 ; Red&nbsp;Hat Press.
		</para>
		 <formalpara id="other-websites">
			<title>Referencing Other Internet Sites</title>
			 <para>
				When referencing another internet site, use the following guidelines:
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Do not link words within the body text. That is, do not use structures such as "Go <ulink url="somewhere.com">here</ulink> for more information," where "here" is a link.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Short URLs, such as <ulink url="http://partner.redhat.com">http://partner.redhat.com</ulink> are OK to use in body text at your discretion.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					If the URL is excessively long, or complex, create a link using the title of the destination as a label, and put the actual URL in a footnote. For example: See the <ulink url="http://world-database-of-everything.com/en/classifcation_of_species/mammals.html"><citetitle>Classification of Species</citetitle></ulink><footnote> <para>
						http://world-database-of-everything.com/en/classifcation_of_species/mammals.html
					</para>
					 </footnote> page for more information.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>

	</section>
	 <section id="other-authors">
		<title>Citing Other Authors</title>
		 <para>
			DocBook provides the &lt;blockquote&gt; and &lt;attribution&gt; tags for this purpose, but how they should be rendered is currently being discussed. For example:
		</para>
		 <blockquote>
			<attribution>Thomas Jefferson</attribution> <para>
				Why use two words when one will do?
			</para>

		</blockquote>

	</section>

</chapter>

