<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="e">
	<title>E</title>
	 <variablelist>
		<varlistentry id="e_book_e_business_e_commerce_e_learning_email">
			<term>e-book, e-business, e-commerce, e-learning, email</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Refer to the primary reference for the type of copy you are creating, either AP or IBM.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="e.g._i.e.">
			<term>e.g., i.e.</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Red&nbsp;Hat technical documentation always expands these abbreviations.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="earlier">
			<term>earlier</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Use to refer to earlier releases of products. Do not use "older" or related terms. See also <xref linkend="later" />.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="emacs">
			<term>Emacs</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					If referring to the program, use "Emacs." For example, "Source-Navigator supports Emacs or vi commands." If referring to the shell prompt command, use "emacs." For example, "At the prompt, type emacs." The complete and correct name is "GNU Emacs."
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="emdash">
			<term>emdash</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Used (informally) to indicate a pause or abrupt change in thought; for emphasis; or to set off a series in a phrase. See <xref linkend="dash" /> for more information.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="ensure">
			<term>ensure</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					This means "to make sure, certain, or safe; to guarantee." For example, "Perform the following steps to ensure a network and serial connection."
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="enter">
			<term>enter</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					When referring to the keyboard key, use <keycap>Enter</keycap>. If referring to the keyboard key on Solaris, use <keycap>Return</keycap>.
				</para>
				 <para>
					When referring to typing a command, use "type" instead, such as "To open Source-Navigator from the command line, type <command>snavigator</command>."
				</para>
				 <para>
					When typing information into a single-field dialog box, "enter" means "type and press <keycap>Enter</keycap>." An example is "enter the license number." For multi-field dialog boxes, see "type."
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="environment">
			<term>environment</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The state of a computer, usually determined by which programs are running and basic hardware and software characteristics. For example, when one speaks of running a program in a UNIX environment, it means running a program on a computer that has the UNIX operating system.
				</para>
				 <para>
					One ingredient of an environment, therefore, is the operating system. But operating systems include a number of different parameters. For example, many operating systems allow you to choose your command prompt or a default command path. All these parameters taken together constitute the environment.
				</para>
				 <para>
					Another term for environment in this sense is platform.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="essentially">
			<term>essentially</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="ethernet">
			<term>Ethernet</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>n.</emphasis> Uppercase "E" at all times.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="event">
			<term>event</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					An action or occurrence detected by a program. Events can be user actions, such as clicking a mouse button or pressing a key, or system occurrences, such as running out of memory.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="exclamation_points_">
			<term>exclamation points (!)</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use at the end of sentences. An exclamation point can be used when referring to a command, such as the bang (!) command.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="Exec-Shield">
			<term>Exec-Shield</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Exec-Shield is a security-enhancing modification to the Linux kernel that makes large parts of specially-marked programs including their stack not executable.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="execute">
			<term>execute</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Has the same meaning as run. Execute means to perform an action, as in executing a program or a command.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="exif">
			<term>Exif</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. Do not use "EXIF." Exif is an image file format specification that enables metadata tags to be added to existing JPEG, TIFF and RIFF files. Sometimes to referred to as "Exif Print."
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="extranet">
			<term>extranet</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Refers to an intranet that is partially accessible to authorized outsiders. Whereas an intranet resides behind a firewall and is accessible only to people who are members of the same company or organization, an extranet provides various levels of accessibility to outsiders. You can access an extranet only if you have a valid user name and password, and your identity determines which parts of the extranet you can view.
				</para>
				 <para>
					Capitalize only at the beginning of a sentence.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>

	</variablelist>
</chapter>

