<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="easily_confused_words">
	<title>Easily Confused Words</title>
	 <para>
		This section identifies some easily confused words and how to choose the correct term for your situation.
	</para>
	 <formalpara id="affect_and_effect">
		<title>Affect and Effect</title>
		 <para>
			Each of these words can be used as a verb or a noun, but they are not always interchangeable.
		</para>

	</formalpara>
	 <variablelist>
		<varlistentry id="affect_n._v.">
			<term>affect (n., v.)</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					As a noun, refers to the emotional impact of an action. Unless you are writing a psychology article, this is unlikely to be the choice for you.
				</para>
				 <para>
					As a verb, means to have an influence on something, or to cause something to change.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="effect_n._v.">
			<term>effect (n., v.)</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					As a noun, refers to the result of some action. For example, "the team members discussed the effect of the new policy on their working conditions."
				</para>
				 <para>
					As a verb, means to produce a result, or to cause something to happen. For example, "the CEO claimed that the new policy would effect a positive economic outcome."
				</para>
				 <para>
					The use of "effect" as a verb is less common than the use of "affect," and there are usually alternatives that are clearer. For example, "the CEO claimed that the new policy would produce a positive economic outcome."
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>

	</variablelist>
	 <formalpara id="assure_ensure_and_insure">
		<title>Assure, Ensure, and Insure</title>
		 <para>
			These are relatively easy to get right, but here are some quick definitions.
		</para>

	</formalpara>
	 <variablelist>
		<varlistentry id="assure_v.">
			<term>assure (v.)</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					"Assure" suggests mental comfort. For example, "I assured my future father-in-law that I would eventually find a job."
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="ensure_v.">
			<term>ensure (v.)</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					"Ensure" means to make sure of something, to be certain that something exists or some condition has been met.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="insure_v.">
			<term>insure (v.)</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					"Insure" relates to monetary insurance.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>

	</variablelist>

</section>

