<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="grammar">
	<title>Grammar</title>
	 <para>
		This section contains information on a few common grammar topics. For subjects not covered here, consult The Chicago Manual of Style, 17th Edition.
	</para>
	 <section id="active-voice">
		<title>Active Voice</title>
		 <para>
			Use the active voice ("Type ... to start Linuxconf") rather than passive ("Linuxconf can be started by typing ...") whenever possible. Active voice makes for more lively, interesting reading. It is more compelling than passive voice and helps to reduce word count.
		</para>
		 <para>
			This does not mean that the passive voice is forbidden. There are situations when using the passive voice is appropriate, such as release notes, technical notes, and similar material.
		</para>
		 <para>
			For example, the sentence, "The Developer Center, a site for reference material and other resources, has been introduced to the OpenShift website." reads better than
		</para>
		 <para>
			"The OpenShift website introduces the Developer Center, a site for reference material and other resources." Here, the passive voice is better because the important issue ("The Developer Center") is the subject of the sentence.
		</para>
		 <para>
			You can also use the passive voice to front-load important keywords in key areas of your content, such as the title, heading, or at the beginning of a paragraph or sentence. You need to make these decisions on a case-by-case basis, weighing the importance of front-loading keywords against content that is readable (that is, not awkward sounding). Consider the following two examples:
		</para>
		 <example id="active-voice-example">
			<title>Active Voice</title>
			 <para>
				"Dutch hosting provider Oxilion launches <emphasis>public cloud</emphasis> service based on Red&nbsp;Hat Enterprise&nbsp;Virtualization."
			</para>

		</example>
		 <example id="passive-voice-example">
			<title>Passive Voice</title>
			 <para>
				"<emphasis>Public cloud</emphasis> service based on Red&nbsp;Hat Enterprise&nbsp;Virtualization launched by Dutch hosting provider Oxilion."
			</para>

		</example>

	</section>
	 <section id="agreement">
		<title>Agreement</title>
		 <para>
			In grammar, agreement occurs when specific parts of a sentence are coordinated; that is, they agree in number and gender.
		</para>
		 <para>
			There are two forms of agreement: <emphasis>subject-verb agreement</emphasis> and <emphasis>pronoun-antecedent agreement</emphasis>. Subject-verb agreement is pretty rudimentary, and is not discussed here. Pronoun-antecedent agreement can be a little more problematic, so...
		</para>
		 <section id="pronoun-antecedent-agreement">
			<title>Pronoun-antecedent agreement</title>
			 <para>
				A <emphasis>pronoun</emphasis> is a word that is used in place of a noun (for example, I, he, she, it). An <emphasis>antecedent</emphasis> is a word or phrase to which the pronoun refers.
			</para>
			 <para>
				When you are comfortable with subject-verb agreement, pronoun-antecedent agreement often follows as a matter of course.
			</para>
			 <para>
				The following is an annotated roundup of pronoun-antecedent rules:
			</para>
			 <formalpara id="singular-plural-nouns">
				<title>Singular and Plural Nouns</title>
				 <para>
					A singular pronoun refers to a singular antecedent; a plural pronoun refers to a plural antecedent. For example:
				</para>

			</formalpara>
			 <itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The CD spins in <emphasis>its</emphasis> caddy. (The singular third-person pronoun "its" refers to the singular antecedent "CD".)
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						The developers checked <emphasis>their</emphasis> work. (The plural third-person pronoun "their" refers to the plural antecedent "developers".)
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>
			 <formalpara id="collective-nouns">
				<title>Collective Nouns</title>
				 <para>
					When collective nouns are used as antecedents, use singular or plural pronouns, depending on the sentence's meaning. For example:
				</para>

			</formalpara>
			 <itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Microsoft seems second to none in <emphasis>its</emphasis> marketing skills. (The collective noun "Microsoft" takes the singular pronoun "its" because the collective noun refers to the group as a whole.)
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						The developers were asked for <emphasis>their</emphasis> preferences. (The collective noun "developers" takes the plural pronoun "their" because the reference is to the individuals of the group.)
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>

		</section>

	</section>
	 <section id="countable-nouns">
		<title>Countable Nouns</title>
		 <para>
			For nouns that are not countable, it is correct to use "less" and "amount", for example "less memory" or "the required amount of memory".
			For nouns that are countable, use "fewer" instead of "less", and use "number" instead of "amount".
		</para>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> This passphrase configuration can improve security by providing less opportunities for someone else to see you type the passphrase. </entry>
						 <entry> This passphrase configuration can improve security by providing fewer opportunities for someone else to see you type the passphrase. </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> Vim has fast, efficient keystrokes to delete an exact amount of words, lines, sentences, or paragraphs. </entry>
						 <entry> Vim has fast, efficient keystrokes to delete an exact number of words, lines, sentences, or paragraphs. </entry>

					</row>					

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>

	</section>
	<section id ="possessives">
	<title> Possessives</title>
	<para>
	Possessives are when singular and plural nouns have an appostrophe and s (these two components appear after a singular noun whereas the appostrophe comes after the letter s in a plural noun) to show that something or someone belongs to a person or thing. However, consider avoidng using these terms in the following scenario.
	</para>
	<section id="no-posessives-with-abbreviations-and-product-names">
	<title> Abbreviations and Product Names</title>
<para> 
Avoid using possessives to refer to abbreviations and product names
</para>
 <para>
	<emphasis>Examples:</emphasis>
		</para>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
				You can find NASA documentation on GitHub.
				</para>
<para> The OpenSauced Chrome Extension is the best tool to display your open source contributions.
</para>
			</listitem>
			</section>
			<section id="use-posessives-with-inanimate-objects-and-people">
			<title> People and Inanimate Objects</title>
			<para> Even though possessives cannot be used with product names and abbreviations, they can be used with people and inanimate objects.
			<para>
	<emphasis>Examples:</emphasis>
		</para>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
				Eddie Jaoude's YouTube channel is one of the best sources for learning how to use GitHub.
				</para>
<para> The alt tag's text for the Pepsi logo is too short.
</para>
			</listitem>
			</section>
	</section> 
	 <section id="using-who-whom">
		<title>Using Who, Whom, That, and Which Correctly</title>
		 <para>
			Use "whom" or "who" to introduce a qualifying phrase when the antecedent is a person. Use "that" or "which" when referring to a thing. Use "which" or "that" to introduce a qualifying phrase when the antecedent is a concept or an object. Who, whom, that, and which are known as "relative pronouns".
		</para>
		 <para>
			Use the following as guidelines:
		</para>
		 <variablelist>
			<varlistentry id="using-who">
				<term> Who </term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Relative pronoun when persons are the subject.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>
			 <varlistentry id="using-whom">
				<term> Whom </term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Relative pronoun when persons are not the subject.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>
			 <varlistentry id="using-which">
				<term> Which </term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Relative pronoun for things.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>
			 <varlistentry id="using-that">
				<term> That </term>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						Restrictive pronoun for things.
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</varlistentry>

		</variablelist>
		 <para>
			<emphasis>Examples:</emphasis>
		</para>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The jewel case, which previously held the CD, was broken recently.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The CD that I received for my birthday is defective.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Edward C. Bailey, who wrote "Maximum RPM",...
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The company that published "Maximum RPM" was...
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					This book belongs to whomever purchased it last week.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Who ate all the cereal?
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					To whom should I address the letter?
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The desktop that was designed by Earl is not called GNOME.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The GNOME developers who worked on the desktop are...
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The GNOME developers to whom they owe gratitude are...
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <note>
			<para>
				To help you choose between <emphasis>who</emphasis> and <emphasis>whom</emphasis>, substitute the person about whom you are speaking with <emphasis>he</emphasis>, <emphasis>she</emphasis>, <emphasis>him</emphasis>, or <emphasis>her</emphasis>.
			</para>

			 <itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If your restatement contains <emphasis>him</emphasis>, <emphasis>her</emphasis>, <emphasis>them</emphasis>, <emphasis>me</emphasis>, or <emphasis>us</emphasis>, then use <emphasis>whom</emphasis> or <emphasis>whomever</emphasis>. "I'm giving the book to him." "To whom am I giving the book?"
					</para>

				</listitem>
				 <listitem>
					<para>
						If the restatement contains the word <emphasis>he</emphasis>, <emphasis>she</emphasis>, <emphasis>they</emphasis>, <emphasis>I</emphasis>, or <emphasis>we</emphasis>, then use <emphasis>who</emphasis> or <emphasis>whoever</emphasis>. "Do you think he would mind?" "Who do you think would mind?" "She's walking in the door." "Who's walking in the door?"
					</para>

				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>

		</note>
	</section>
	 <section id="sentence-structure">
		<title>Sentence Structure</title>
		 <para>
			A <emphasis>sentence</emphasis> is one complete thought. A sentence expresses something about a subject (a person, place, or thing) and a verb (what the subject is or does).
		</para>
		 <para>
			Consider the following points when constructing sentences:
		</para>
		
		 <formalpara id="length">
			<title>Sentence Length</title>
			 <para>
				Try not to pack too much information into one sentence.
        In technical documentation, try not to exceed 40 words in a sentence.
        Keep it short.
        The following sentence is a bad writing example:
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <para>
			The <guibutton>Start</guibutton> button, which you can find in the bottom left corner of your screen (also activated by the "Windows key" on your keyboard, the one between the <keycap>Ctrl</keycap> and <keycap>Alt</keycap> keys), provides a central starting point for applications and tasks, and can be customized according to your individual preferences so that it presents menu items relevant to you instead of presenting the standard items that come with the default installation of the operating system, items which, in my opinion, are irrelevant for most users these days who really only need access to an internet browser such as Google Chrome or Mozilla Firefox.
		</para>

		 <formalpara id="preposition">
			<title>Preposition at the End of a Sentence</title>
			 <para>
				Allow a preposition at the end of a sentence to avoid otherwise awkward wording.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <para>
			For example, instead of "Click the workspace to which you want to switch", which can sound stilted, it flows better to use "Click the workspace to switch to".
		</para>

		 <formalpara id="run-on">
			<title>Run-on Sentences</title>
			 <para>
				Two or more complete ideas that are joined without punctuation, or separated only by a comma, create a <emphasis>run-on sentence</emphasis> (also called a <emphasis>fused sentence</emphasis>). The sentence does not have to be long to be a run-on sentence, although the longer the sentence the more difficult it is to read. You can:
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Separate independent clauses with a period.
          This creates two sentences from one.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Use semicolons to form a compound sentence.
          Think of a semicolon as an extended breather; it is longer than a comma.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Insert a <firstterm>coordinating conjunction</firstterm>, such as "and" or "but", between the independent clauses to form a compound sentence. For example, "The process starts, but it produces an error."
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Insert a <firstterm>subordinating conjunction</firstterm>, such as "although" or "because", which forms a compound sentence with a subordinate clause. For example, "Although the process starts, it produces an error."
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> The CDs both of which belonged to the developers were in the test lab. </entry>
						 <entry> The CDs, both of which belonged to the developers, were in the test lab. </entry>

					</row>
					 <row>
						<entry> To access your programs click the <guibutton>Start</guibutton> button. </entry>
						 <entry> To access your programs, click <guibutton>Start</guibutton>. </entry>

					</row>
					 <row>
						<entry>The CDs, both of which belonged to the developers, were in the test lab, because they were the only available CDs for the new release, the developers were anxious about keeping them clean. (This sentence exhibits a <firstterm>comma splice</firstterm> which is also often regarded as a run-on sentence.) </entry>
						 <entry>The CDs, both of which belonged to the developers, were in the test lab. Because they were the only available CDs for the new release, the developers were anxious about keeping them clean. </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>
		 <formalpara id="fragments">
			<title>Sentence Fragments</title>
			 <para>
				A <firstterm>sentence fragment</firstterm> is an incomplete sentence.
        For example, "Red&nbsp;Hat releases no upgrade before its time." is a complete sentence, whereas in "We will release no upgrade.
        At least, before its time." the second of the two sentences is a fragment.
        Repair sentence fragments by making them complete sentences.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <note>
			<para>
				Read your sentences aloud, as if each sentence were the *only* sentence on paper.
        If you hear a sentence that does not make any sense by itself, then it is probably a sentence fragment.
			</para>

		</note>
		 <formalpara id="telegraphic">
			<title>Telegraphic Style</title>
			 <para>
				Extreme cases of word economy can result in a telegraphic style, omitting words that can clarify the meaning of a sentence, such as articles, prepositions, and verbs used with gerunds.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> Click button to start. </entry>
						 <entry> Click <guibutton>Start</guibutton> to start the process. </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>
		 <para>
			This problem is often encountered in the Revision History. It is important that wording in the Revision History is clear for translators and customers to understand.
		</para>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> Minor revision - missing element items </entry>
						 <entry> Minor revision - added missing element items </entry>

					</row>
					 <row>
						<entry> Some further work required to avoid 404s at lower levels of the SDK. </entry>
						 <entry> Some further work required to avoid 404 errors at lower levels of the SDK. </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>

<!-- Added section about avoiding causative verbs -->
		 <formalpara id="causative">
			<title>Causative Verbs</title>
			 <para>
				Avoid the construction "have something happen". Rewrite to replace "have" with a verb that describes the actual action.  
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> The latter connection has no devices assigned. </entry>
						 <entry> No devices are assigned to the latter connection. </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> To have the changes take effect … </entry>
						 <entry> To apply the changes … </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>

<!-- 	 <formalpara id="condition-action">
			<title>Condition and Action</title>
			 <para>
				A condition should precede an action. A clause that explains "why", or for what purpose, should come before a statement of what the action is or how it is done.  
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> Divide the storage devices into smaller chunks to create a partition. </entry>
						 <entry> To create a partition, divide the storage devices into smaller chunks. </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table> -->

<!-- Added section about "either, or" -->
		 <formalpara id="either-or">
			<title>The Either-Or Construction</title>
			 <para>
				Use the "either x ... or y" construction only to refer to a choice between two options, not for three or more options.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> Scale up by adding more resources, with either more memory, CPUs, or disk space. </entry>
						 <entry> Scale up by adding more resources, such as memory, CPUs, or disk space. </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>

<!-- Added section about "following" -->
		 <formalpara id="following-noun">
			<title>Use of Following</title>
			 <para>
				Use "following" with a noun.
				In a quiz question, "the following" is often superfluous.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> Non-privileged users can use the role to configure the following: </entry>
						 <entry> Non-privileged users can use the role to configure the following interfaces: </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> Which two of the following statements describe the benefits of Linux? </entry>
						 <entry> Which two statements describe the benefits of Linux? </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>

<!-- Added section about "if, then" -->
		 <formalpara id="if-then">
			<title>The If-Then Construction</title>
			 <para>
				Generally, follow an "if" statement with a "then" statement.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> If one service is started, the other is also started. </entry>
						 <entry> If one service is started, then the other is also started. </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>

<!-- Added section about use of relative pronoun "that" -->
		 <formalpara id="that">
			<title>Including That in Clauses</title>
			 <para>
				Include the word "that" in clauses unless it results in writing that is too formal or stilted. 
				Including the conjunction "that" makes the sentence easier to translate and improves clarity for readers whose primary language is not English.  
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> Verify your directory service is working. </entry>
						 <entry> Verify that your directory service is working. </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>

<!-- Added section about use of "this, that, these, those" -->
		 <formalpara id="this-that-these-those">
			<title>Use of This That These Those</title>
			 <para>
				Use "this", "that", "these", or "those" followed by a noun. 
				Doing so improves clarity for readers whose primary language is not English, and improves accuracy of translation into other languages where these words differ based on the gender of the noun that they refer to.  
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> This causes SSH to lose the recorded identities of the remote systems. </entry>
						<entry> 
						 <para>
						 Option 1: This action causes SSH to lose the recorded identities of the remote systems. 
						 </para>
						 <para>
						 Option 2: Consequently, SSH loses the recorded identities of the remote systems.
						 </para>						 
						 </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> A site can use these to self-assign a private routable IP address space inside the organization. </entry>
						 <entry> A site can use these unique local addresses to self-assign a private routable IP address space inside the organization. </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>

		 <formalpara id="verbosity">
			<title> Verbosity </title>
			 <para>
				Avoid unnecessary words. Keep it succinct.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> The <command>fsck /dev/vdb1</command> command performs a file-system check on the XFS file system residing on the <filename>/dev/vdb1</filename> partition. </entry>
						 <entry> The <command>fsck /dev/vdb1</command> command checks the XFS file system on the <filename>/dev/vdb1</filename> partition. </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> Red&nbsp;Hat Insights provides different services for the administration and monitoring of the registered systems that can be used for troubleshooting and even remediation of the issues identified. </entry>
						 <entry> Red&nbsp;Hat Insights services administer and monitor registered systems to troubleshoot and remediate issues. </entry>

					</row>					
					<row>
						<entry> Perform the installation of the product. </entry>
						 <entry> Install the product. </entry>

					 </row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>
		 <formalpara id="word-order">
			<title>Word Order</title>
			 <para>
				When two or more correct arrangements are possible, choose the order that creates the least ambiguity.
        Generally, this is the standard subject-verb-object sequence, with modifiers before or immediately following what they modify.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> To update the address lists might be your primary concern. </entry>
						 <entry> Your primary concern might be to update the address lists. </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>

	</section>

<!-- Moved Ambiguities section to Chapter 4. -->

<!-- Moved "Contractions" content from Usage A-Z list to here. 
Changed "policy manuals" > "technical documentation". 
Split contractions and abbreviations into separate paragraphs. -->
	 <xi:include href="Easily_Confused_Words.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	 <section id="contractions-and-abbreviations">
		<title>Contractions and Abbreviations</title>
		 <para>
			Do not use contractions in Red&nbsp;Hat documents.
      For example, do not use can't, "don't", "won't", and similar examples.
      Write out the words in full.
      Contractions are a mark of informal writing, and should be avoided when writing technical documentation or other more formal types of manuals.
      They can also cause problems for translation. 
		</para>

 		<para>
			Take care also with abbreviations; replace "e.g." with "for example", and replace "i.e." with "that is", and so on. 
		</para>

	</section>
	 <xi:include href="Punctuation.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	 <section id="hyphenation">
		<title>Hyphenation</title>
		 <para>
			No hard and fast rules exist for hyphenation.
      In general, do not hyphenate unless required for clarity, or your other references declare that hyphens are required.
      The following is general guidance; if you are unsure about whether to hyphenate, ask your peers.
      See also the "Hyphens" topic in the <citetitle>IBM Style Guide</citetitle>.
		</para>
		
		 <formalpara id="hyphenate-for-clarity">
			<title>Hyphenate for Clarity</title>
			 <para>
				Hyphenate when needed for clarity. Words that begin with prefixes are usually not hyphenated. Prefixes can include "multi", "non", "sub", "co", "semi", "pre", "re", and so on. The same applies to suffixes; for example, "less" as a suffix does not require hyphenation.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <note>
			<para>
				Always use a hyphen if clarity would suffer otherwise. For example, "He recovered his health" versus "He re-covered the leaky roof."<footnote> <para>
					<ulink url="http://www.apstylebook.com/online/?do=entry&amp;id=3542&amp;src=AE">www.apstylebook.com</ulink>
				</para>
				 </footnote>
			</para>

		</note>
		 <formalpara id="hyphenate-complex-adjectives">
			<title>Hyphenate Complex Adjectives</title>
			 <para>
				Hyphenate complex adjectives (compound modifiers). This is when two adjectives work together to modify an object. The hyphen is used when the first adjective modifies the second adjective. For example, cloud-based solutions, right-side paralysis, systemwide menu.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <note>
			<para>
				Do not hyphenate "open source", even when used as a complex adjective.
			</para>
			 <para>
				Do not hyphenate a compound that includes an adverb that ends in <emphasis>-ly</emphasis>, whether it comes before or after the noun, because it is never ambiguous. This is described in Chicago Manual of Style 7.82. For example, "Red&nbsp;Hat Enterprise Linux is a production-ready, commercially supported Linux distribution."
			</para>

		</note>
		 <formalpara id="hyphenate-consecutive-vowels">
			<title>Hyphenate Consecutive Vowel Sounds</title>
			 <para>
				Hyphenate words where the prefix ends in a vowel and the word that follows begins with the same vowel. For example, semi-independent, pre-emptive.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <note>
			<para>
				Exceptions to this rule include <emphasis>cooperate</emphasis> and <emphasis>coordinate.</emphasis>
			</para>

		</note>
		 <formalpara id="hyphenate-mixed-caps">
			<title>Hyphenate Mixed Capitalization</title>
			 <para>
				Hyphenate when the word that follows a prefix is capitalized. For example, un-American, non-British.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <formalpara id="hyphenate-double-prefixes">
			<title>Hyphenate Double Prefixes</title>
			 <para>
				Hyphenate when the word has double prefixes. For example, sub-subparagraph, re-sublet.
			</para>

		</formalpara>

	</section> 
	 <section id="pronouns-gender-references">
		<title>Pronouns and Gender References</title>
		 <para>
			Do not use gender-specific pronouns in documentation, except to refer to a specific named user, such as in a case study.
      It is easier to read a sentence that uses "they" and "their" rather than "he/she" and "his/hers".
      It is acceptable to use "they" to refer to one person, with a plural verb. 
		</para>
		 <para>			
			Usually, when giving instructions, use the imperative mood or use "you".
      In more general explanations, you can use "users" or "new users".
      Do not use "one" in place of "you" when writing technical documentation, because it is too formal.
      Do not use "it" to refer to a person.
		</para>
		 <para>
			Avoid first person "I, we, our".
      Use second person "you" whenever possible. 
		</para>
		 <para>
			If referring to what Red&nbsp;Hat does, use "Red&nbsp;Hat" followed by a singular verb. 
		</para>	

		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					 <row>
						<entry> An engineer must be trained on the equipment that he services. </entry>
						 <entry> Engineers must be trained on the equipment that they service. </entry>

					</row>			
					<row>
						<entry> In the web console, we can restart or shut down the system. </entry>
						 <entry> In the web console, you can restart or shut down the system. </entry>

					</row>
					 <row>
						<entry> We recommend that you generate a service account for each microservice in your project. </entry>
						 <entry> Red&nbsp;Hat recommends that you generate a service account for each microservice in your project. </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>			
	
	</section>
	 <section id="tense">
		<title>Tense</title>
		 <para>
			Avoid future tense (or using the term "will") whenever possible.
      For example, future tense ("The window will open ...") does not read as well as the present tense ("The window opens ...").
      Remember, the users you are writing for most often refer to the documentation while they are using the system, not after or in advance of using the system.
		</para>

		 <para>
			Use simple present tense as much as possible.
      It avoids problems with consequences and time-related communications, and is the easiest tense for translation.
		</para>
		 <para>
			<ulink url="https://github.com/StyleGuides/WritingStyleGuide/issues">Report an issue</ulink>
		</para>

	</section> 

</chapter>
