<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="l">
	<title>L</title>
	 <variablelist>
		<varlistentry id="lan">
			<term>LAN</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. This is an acronym for Local Area Network. Do not use Lan or lan.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="latency">
			<term>latency</term>
			 <listitem>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							In general, the period of time that one component in a system is spinning its wheels waiting for another component. Latency, therefore, is wasted time. For example, in accessing data on a disk, latency is defined as the time it takes to position the proper sector under the read/write head.
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							In networking, the amount of time it takes a packet to travel from source to destination. Together, latency and bandwidth define the speed and capacity of a network.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</itemizedlist>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="later">
			<term>later</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Use to refer to later or more recent releases of products. Do not use "newer" or related terms. See also <xref linkend="earlier" />.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="leave-out">
			<term>leave out</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use. Use "omit" instead.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="left-click">
			<term>left-click</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>v.</emphasis> Write the term hyphenated. Do not use "left click" or "leftclick".
				</para>

			</listitem>

<!-- What about "legacy"? -->

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="libreoffice">
			<term>LibreOffice</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					A Linux desktop suite. Do not use "Libre", "Libreoffice", or "Libre Office".
				</para>
				 <para>
					See also <xref linkend="openoffice" />
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="license">
			<term>license</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>n., v.</emphasis> Use this form for both the noun and the verb.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		<!-- Changed to one word -->
		 <varlistentry id="lifecycle">
			<term>lifecycle</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>n., adj.</emphasis> One word.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="like">
			<term>lifecycle</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Avoid "like" to mean "such as". 
					For example, instead of "Namespaces can include resources like network interfaces", use "Namespaces can include resources such as network interfaces".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>		
		 <varlistentry id="linux">
			<term>Linux</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Correct. Do not use "LINUX" or "linux" unless referring to a command, such as "To start Linux, type <command>linux</command>."
				</para>
				 <para>
					Linux is a registered trademark of Linus Torvalds. Use a registered trademark symbol on first use.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="load">
			<term>load</term>
			 <listitem>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							To copy a program from a storage device into memory. Every program must be loaded into memory before it can be executed. Usually the loading process is performed invisibly by a part of the operating system called the <emphasis>loader</emphasis>.
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis>v.</emphasis> In programming, "to load" means to move from one storage type to another storage type for use.
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis>n.</emphasis> The measurement of how any finite resource is being used. For example, the amount of data (traffic) that the network carries, or the amount of CPU in use at any given time.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</itemizedlist>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="load-balancing">
			<term>load balancing</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Distributing processing and communications activity evenly across a computer network so that no single device is overwhelmed. Load balancing is especially important for networks where it is difficult to predict the number of requests that are issued to a server. Busy websites typically employ two or more web servers in a load balancing scheme. If one server starts to get swamped, requests are forwarded to another server with more capacity. Load balancing can also refer to the communications channels themselves.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="logical-topology">
			<term>logical topology</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Also called signal topology. Every LAN has a topology, which refers to the way that the devices on a network are arranged and how they communicate with each other. The physical topology is the way that the workstations are connected to the network through the cables that transmit data: the physical structure of the network. The logical topology, in contrast, is the way that the signals act on the network media, or the way that the data passes through the network from one device to the next without regard to the physical interconnection of the devices.
				</para>

			</listitem>

<!-- Added entries for "log in" and "log in to". -->
		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="login">
			<term>login, log in</term>
			 <listitem>
				 <para>
					Write as one word as an adjective or noun, or as two words as a verb.
				</para>
				 <itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis>adj., n.</emphasis> One word. For example, "the login credentials".
						</para>
					</listitem>

					<listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis>v.</emphasis> Two words. For example, "to log in as root".
						</para>

					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>	

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="log-in-to">
			<term>log in to</term>
			 <listitem>
				 <para>
					<emphasis>v.</emphasis> Write as three words. For example, "to log in to the system".
				</para>
			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="look-at">
			<term>look at</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use. Use "examine" or "inspect" or some other more precise term instead.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="lookup">
			<term>lookup, look-up, look up</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>n.</emphasis> Use the one-word form.
				</para>
				 <para>
					<emphasis>v.</emphasis> Use the two-word form.
				</para>
				 <para>
					<emphasis>adj.</emphasis> Hyphenate when used as a modifier. For example, "a look-up table".
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="loopback-address">
			<term>loopback address</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The loopback address is a special IP address (127.0.0.1 for IPv4, ::1 for IPv6) that is designated for the software loopback interface of a machine. No hardware is associated with a loopback interface, and it is not physically connected to a network.
				</para>
				 <para>
					With a loopback interface, IT professionals can test IP software without concern for broken or corrupted drivers or hardware.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="lots-of">
			<term>lots of</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do not use. Use "many" instead.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>
		 <varlistentry id="lpar">
			<term>LPAR</term>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Abbreviation of "logical partitioning", a system of taking a computer's total resources, such as processors, memory, and storage, and splitting them into smaller units that can be run with their own instance of the operating system and applications. Logical partitioning, which requires specialized hardware circuits, is typically used to separate different functions of a system, such as web serving, database functions, client/server actions, or systems that serve multiple time zones or languages. Logical partitioning can also keep testing environments separated from production environments. Because the partitions act as separate physical machines, they can communicate with each other. Logical partitioning was first used in 1976 by IBM.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</varlistentry>

	</variablelist>
</chapter>

