<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="punctuation">
	<title>Punctuation</title>
	 <para>
		This section contains information on common punctuation topics. For more information, consult The Chicago Manual of Style, 17th Edition.
	</para>
	 <section id="colons-and-semicolons">
		<title>Colons and Semicolons</title>
		 <para>
			Current standards allow the use of a colon or semicolon in a range of different circumstances. Some of these are described in the following sections.
		</para>
		 <formalpara>
			<title> To relate clauses:</title>
			 <para>
				The following sentences show a connection or shared theme between two clauses, or use the second clause to reiterate or amplify the idea in the first clause:
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					They had been writing code all night: this factor could explain their bloodshot eyes.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					They had been writing code all night; this factor could explain their bloodshot eyes.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					I spend a lot of money on food; last month, I went out to eat 36 times.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					I spend a lot of money on food: last month, I went out to eat 36 times.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <para>
			The phrase following a semicolon or colon should begin with a lowercase letter, unless it begins with a proper noun. In the case of a colon, use an uppercase letter if the phrase constitutes a complete sentence on its own.
		</para>
		 <para>
			Try to limit your use of colons and semicolons. Separate sentences with a period if possible.
		</para>
		 <formalpara>
			<title>To introduce a list or series:</title>
			 <para>
				A colon is generally used before a list or series.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The Triangle Area consists of three cities: Raleigh, Durham, and Chapel Hill.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <para>
			Do not use a colon if the list is a complement or object of an element in the sentence.
		</para>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Before going on vacation, be sure to (1) set the alarm, (2) cancel the newspaper, and (3) ask a neighbor to collect your mail.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					The colors I hate most are:
				</para>
				 <itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							green
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							orange
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							pink
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							magenta
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</itemizedlist>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <para>
			Use a colon after "as follows" and "the following" if the related list immediately follows the stem, or introductory sentence.
		</para>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The steps for changing directories are as follows:
				</para>
				 <orderedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Open a terminal.
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							Type <command>cd Documents/Books</command>.
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</orderedlist>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <para>
			Use a colon to introduce a bullet list.
		</para>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					In the Properties dialog box, notice the following entries:
				</para>
				 <itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							Connection name
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							Count
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							Confirm starting connection
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							Confirm stopping connection
						</para>

					</listitem>
					 <listitem>
						<para>
							Cost per
						</para>

					</listitem>

				</itemizedlist>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <para>
			Use a semicolon to separate items in a series if the items contain commas.
		</para>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Everyday I have coffee, toast, and fruit for breakfast; a salad for lunch; and a peanut butter sandwich, cookies, ice cream, and chocolate cake for dinner.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <para>
			Use a semicolon before a conjunctive adverb, such as <emphasis>however, therefore, otherwise, namely, for example</emphasis>, and so on.
		</para>

		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					I think; therefore, I am.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>

	</section>
	 <section id="commas">
		<title>Commas</title>
		 <formalpara id="compound-sentences">
			<title>In compound sentences:</title>
			 <para>
				Use a comma to join clauses in a compound sentence, unless the clauses are short and have a similar theme.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					I spent five hours working on this document, but I lost it when my computer crashed.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Do you want to go the mall and the grocery store with me, or are you going to watch football instead?
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					You play and I'll sing.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <para>
			A comma can be omitted from a sentence with several clauses, but only when there is little chance that the sentence could be misread without it.
		</para>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					We played football all afternoon and were completely exhausted but we still stayed up watching movies all night.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <para>
			That sentence is acceptable, but adding a comma before "... but we still stayed up ..." would provide a pause and avoid the chance of having it read like a run-on sentence.
		</para>
		 <para>
			In a compound sentence that contains several short independent clauses, separate the clauses with commas and use a comma before the conjunction.
		</para>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					You need to go to the grocery store for milk, drop off my dry cleaning, and pick up your little sister from soccer practice.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <formalpara id="adverbial-clauses">
			<title>In adverbial clauses and phrases:</title>
			 <para>
				If a dependent clause is restrictive (omission affects the meaning of the main clause), do not set it off with commas. If it is nonrestrictive (omission does not affect the main clause), set it off with commas:
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					I'll go to lunch with you if we can get pizza.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					I don't want to go out for pizza, because I had pizza yesterday.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <para>
			If a dependent clause comes before the main clause, use a comma whether the clause is restrictive or not.
		</para>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					If we get pizza, I'll go to lunch with you.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					When I heard the voice on the other end of the line, I was quite surprised.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <formalpara id="adjectival-clauses">
			<title>In adjectival clauses or phrases:</title>
			 <para>
				An adjectival clause that can be dropped without changing the meaning of the sentence is set off with commas.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The application, which comes with excellent documentation, is used by many graphic artists.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <para>
			An adjectival clause that cannot be dropped without changing the meaning of the sentence is not set off with commas:
		</para>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The plan that matters most to us will be easy to implement.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <formalpara id="coordinate-adjectives">
			<title>With coordinate adjectives:</title>
			 <para>
				Separate coordinate adjectives (two or more adjectives modifying the same noun) with commas.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					My dog is loyal, obedient, and affectionate.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					It was a long, boring meeting.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <formalpara id="series-lists">
			<title>With series and lists:</title>
			 <para>
				Separate elements in a series of three or more with commas, including a comma before the conjunction if one is used.
			</para>

		</formalpara>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Today I am wearing socks, shoes, pants, and a shirt.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>

	</section>
	 <section id="parentheses">
		<title>Parentheses</title>
		 <para>
			Parentheses are similar to commas in that they set off information that further explains or enhances a statement. Information that is closely related to the statement should be set off with commas; information that is more incidental should be set off with parentheses.
		</para>

		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					I tried to get to the elevator before the door shut, but I was too slow.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Most of my favorite authors (Shakespeare, Dickens, Woolf) are dead.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <para>
			Expressions beginning with <emphasis>for example, that is</emphasis> and so on can be set off with parentheses if they cause a major break in the sentence. If the break is minor, use commas.
		</para>

		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					He interviewed the biggest stars of the day, namely, Madonna, Johnny Cash, and Jack Nicholson.
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					Classic works of literature (such as Dickens, Shakespeare, the Brontes) lined the shelves.
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <para>
			If the contents of the parentheses include at least one complete sentence, the period goes inside the parentheses. If not, the period goes outside.
		</para>

	</section>
	 <section id="quotation-marks">
		<title>Quotation Marks</title>

<!-- Previous guidance
		 <para>
			Commas and periods go inside quotation marks.
		</para>
 		 <para>
			Question marks, exclamation points, dashes, and semicolons go inside the quotation marks if they are part of the quotation; if not, they go outside. 
		</para> -->
 		 <para>
			When indicating the start or end of a direct quotation, use curly quotation marks. 
			In all other contexts, such as when writing code samples, code syntax, hexadecimal numbers, or hypertext links, use straight quotation marks.
			Refer to the "Typographical Considerations" section in the "Quotation Marks" topic in the <citetitle>IBM Style Guide</citetitle>. 
		</para>
		 <para>
			In technical documentation, place punctuation marks, including periods, commas, question marks, exclamation points, dashes, and semicolons inside the quotation marks if they are part of the quotation or part of a programming element that uses quotation marks; if not, place punctuation marks outside the quotation marks. 
			If a sentence ends with a quotation, use only one punctuation mark to end the sentence, and place it inside the closing quotation mark if it is part of the quotation, or outside if it is not.

		</para> 
		<example><title>Correct Examples of the Use of Punctuation with Quotation Marks</title>
        <para>
        For bind mounts, add "bind" and set <command>fstype</command> to "none".
        </para>
		<screen>
		Login successful.
		...output omitted...
		Using project "default".
        </screen>
		<para>
		As you can see in the previous image, the title of the web page is "OpenShift 3 Etherpad".
		</para>
		<para>
		In the program segment, ensure that the value is X'FF'.
    	</para>		
		<!-- <para>
		If you use the keyword operand PGMID="PAYCOM", you must ...
    	</para> -->
		<para>
		Julius Caesar said, “I came. I saw. I conquered.”
    	</para>
    	</example> 

	</section>
<!-- Add examples of when to use or not to use quotation marks. 
		<example><title>Correct Examples of the Use of Quotation Marks</title>
        <para>
        For example, the following message indicates multiple possible solutions: "This message could be resolved by changing the time."  
        </para>
		<para>
        In this example, the final period is not part of the command in the quoted text: Use "xemacs" only when referring to a command, such as "To start XEmacs, type xemacs".  
        </para>
      	</example> 

 	 	 <para>
			Do not put quotation marks around cliches or slang terms (in fact, avoid using cliches and slang as it makes the translation of content more difficult).
		</para>
Remove this sentence, and leave it to chapter 4 to cover avoidance of slang. 		

		 <para>
			A word or words being introduced to readers should not be placed in quotation marks. In DocBook, use the &lt;firstterm&gt; element for first reference. If you are writing outside of the SGML tagging environment, use quotation marks for first references. Subsequent references do not need quotation marks or the &lt;firstterm&gt; element.
		</para>
Deleted paragraph now that DocBook tagging no longer applies. -->		

	 <section id="apostrophes">
		<title>Apostrophes</title>
		<para>
			Do not use an apostrophe to denote a plural. 
		</para>
		<para>
			To denote a possessive, use an apostrophe as follows: 
		</para>
		 <para>
			Plural nouns not ending in <emphasis>s</emphasis> should add an <emphasis>'s </emphasis> (for example, the alumni's contribution).
		</para>
		 <para>
			Plural nouns ending in <emphasis>s</emphasis> only need an apostrophe (for example, the horses' food).
		</para>
		 <para>
			Singular common nouns ending in <emphasis>s</emphasis> should add an <emphasis>'s</emphasis> unless the next word begins with an <emphasis>s</emphasis> (for example, the witness's answer or the witness' story).
		</para>
		 <para>
			Singular proper names ending in <emphasis>s</emphasis> only need an apostrophe (for example, Dickens' novels).
		</para>

	</section>

<!-- Moved from A-Z section to add here instead -->
	 <section id="exclamation">
		<title>Exclamation Points</title>
		<para>
			Do not use at the end of sentences. An exclamation point can be used when referring to a command, such as the bang (!) command.
		</para>

	</section>

<!-- Added section -->
 	 <section id="referring">
		<title>Referring to Punctuation Marks</title>
		<para>
			To refer to a punctuation mark or special character, use its name alone if it is one of the following standard characters:
		</para>
		<para>
			. , : ; ' " ( ) [ ] { } ! ?
		</para>
		<para>
			For another character, use its name followed by the symbol in parentheses.  
		</para>
		<para>
			Do not use the symbol on its own.   
		</para>
		<example><title>Referring to Punctuation Marks</title>

          <para>
            Use a semicolon to separate two parts of a sentence that can each stand on their own.
          </para>
		  <para>
            The path contains the library qualifier in braces.
          </para>
          </example>
		<para>
			For more details, see the <citetitle>IBM Style Guide</citetitle>.
		</para>

	</section>

<!-- Added section -->
	 <section id="punc-names">
		<title>Names of Punctuation Marks and Special Characters</title>
		<para>
			Use the names in the following table to refer to punctuation marks or special characters:
		</para>	

<!-- If possible, reduce width of first column. -->
		<table>
			<title>Names of Punctuation Marks and Special Characters</title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				 <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
    			 <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="2.0*"/>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Symbol </entry>
						 <entry> Name </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> &amp; </entry>
						 <entry> Ampersand </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> &lt; &gt; </entry>
						 <entry> Angle brackets </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> &apos; </entry>
						 <entry> Apostrophe </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> * </entry>
						 <entry> Asterisk </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> &commat; </entry>
						 <entry> At sign </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> &bsol; </entry>
						 <entry> Backslash </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> &grave; </entry>
						 <entry> Backtick </entry>

					</row>					
					<row>
						<entry> { } </entry>
						 <entry> Braces </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> [ ] </entry>
						 <entry> Brackets </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> ^ </entry>
						 <entry> Caret </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> &#x2713; </entry>
						 <entry> Check mark </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> : </entry>
						 <entry> Colon </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> , </entry>
						 <entry> Comma </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> &quot; </entry>
						 <entry> Double quotation mark </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> ... </entry>
						 <entry> Ellipsis </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> &mdash; </entry>
						 <entry> Em dash </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> &ndash; </entry>
						 <entry> En dash </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> = </entry>
						 <entry> Equal sign </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> &excl; </entry>
						 <entry> Exclamation point </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> &sol; </entry>
						 <entry> Forward slash </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> &gt; </entry>
						 <entry> Greater than symbol </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> - </entry>
						 <entry> Hyphen or minus sign </entry>

					</row>					
					<row>
						<entry> &lt; </entry>
						 <entry> Less than symbol </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> &num; </entry>
						 <entry> Number sign; use <emphasis>hash</emphasis> to refer to a hashtag in social media </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> ( ) </entry>
						 <entry> Parentheses </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> % </entry>
						 <entry> Percent sign </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> . </entry>
						 <entry> Period; dot (when not referring to punctuation) </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> + </entry>
						 <entry> Plus sign </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> ? </entry>
						 <entry> Question mark </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> ; </entry>
						 <entry> Semicolon </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> &apos; </entry>
						 <entry> Single quotation mark </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> ~ </entry>
						 <entry> Tilde </entry>

					</row>
					<row>
						<entry> _ </entry>
						 <entry> Underscore </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>

	</section>

</section>