<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Conventions_for_Writers_and_Editors.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="writing_clearly_and_succinctly">
	<title>Writing Clearly and Succinctly</title>
	 <para>
		This chapter provides guidelines, tips, and techniques to help to make your writing easier to read and understand, and also to translate.
	</para>
	 <section id="Writing_Clearly_and_Succinctly-Sentence_Structure">
		<title>Sentence Structure</title>
    <para>
      This section describes how to construct your content for clarity and readability.
      A full discussion of this topic is beyond the scope of this guide.
    </para>

		 <section id="Sentence_Structure-Using_Lists_Correctly">
			<title>Using and Formatting Lists</title>
			 <para>
				Lists appear in a range of formats, such as series, ordered, unordered (bulleted), and so on.
        Avoid using bulleted lists to format a single sentence.
        Some translation tools display list items and the introductory sentence (or <firstterm>sentence stem</firstterm>) as individual sentences for translation.
        If they are not complete sentences, they can be difficult to translate.
			</para>
      <para>
        The following general guidelines apply to lists:
      </para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Bulleted lists</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                  Use this list type when the order of items is not important.
				  In most cases, a bulleted list should have three or more entries.
				  In limited cases, specific publications might choose instead to allow fewer entries in a list.
                  Titles are optional.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Ordered lists</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    These appear as numbered lists.
                    Use this list type for multiple entries if you need to refer to one of the entries from elsewhere in your document, or where order is important.
                    For example, use an ordered list for a sequence of steps to complete a task, or for a sequence of events.
                    Titles are optional.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Variable lists</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                  These appear as a list of terms followed by definitions.
                  Use this list type to list and describe a series of terms, such as variables, command options or arguments, and similar items.
                  Titles are optional.
                  (This list is written as a variable list.)
                  A variable list is often preferable to a table, because tables have the additional overhead of calculating column width for every translation.
                  Tables are best reserved for information that relies on, or benefits greatly from, a grid layout.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
            <term>Procedures</term>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    These appear as a list of numbered steps.
                    Procedures always include a title, and are used to list the required steps to achieve a task.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
    <para>
        You can nest lists, but try to keep the number of levels to two or fewer.
    </para>
    <section><title>Formatting Lists for Readability</title>
      <para>
        It is important to provide enough spacing between elements in your documents to facilitate reading and comprehension.
        You can include a lot of information in a few short paragraphs but readers need to be able to process that information in chunks.
        The same consideration applies to lists.
      </para>
      <para>
        In some authoring environments, you can choose between normal or compact spacing for lists.
		Use a list with normal spacing if any list item contains the following components:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Nested lists.
            Nested list items themselves can use the <option>compact</option> attribute if they fall outside the bounds of these recommendations.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Navigation or similar instructions (such as "Go to Menu -> Submenu").
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Multiple paragraphs, or sentences that wrap to two or more lines.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Other sections where your deliverables might benefit from more spacing between list items, for example a list of objectives in a training course.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
        Use a list with compact spacing in all other cases.
      </para>
      <note>
        <para>
          The use of all but the simplest graphics in lists is strongly discouraged.
        </para>
      </note>

		 <para>
			The following explanation provides some initial guidance for using lists correctly. 
			For a detailed explanation, refer to <ulink url="https://www.ibm.com/docs/en/ibm-style?topic=format-lists"><citetitle>Lists</citetitle></ulink> in <citetitle>IBM Style</citetitle>
         	<guiicon><inlinemediaobject>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata fileref="images/padlock.png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </inlinemediaobject></guiicon>.
		</para>
		 <para>
			Do not insert a list midway through a sentence and then continue the sentence after the list.
		</para>		
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> <para>
							Before you start the installation, ensure that you have
						</para>
						 <itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									enough free storage on your system
								</para>

							</listitem>
							 <listitem>
								<para>
									backed up any data that you want to keep
								</para>

							</listitem>

						</itemizedlist>
						 <para>
							to ensure a smooth installation.
						</para>
						 </entry>
						 <entry> <para>
							Before you start the installation, follow these prerequisite steps:
						</para>
						 <itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									Ensure that you have enough free storage on your system.
								</para>

							</listitem>
							 <listitem>
								<para>
									Back up any data that you want to keep.
								</para>

							</listitem>

						</itemizedlist>
						 </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>
		 <para>
			For a lead-in sentence that introduces a list, use a complete sentence. A lead-in that is a sentence fragment can be difficult to translate into other languages.
		</para>	
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> <para>
							Non-privileged users can use the role to configure:
						</para>
						 <itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									Interface 1		
								</para>

							</listitem>
							 <listitem>
								<para>	
									Interface 2
								</para>

							</listitem>

						</itemizedlist>						
						 </entry>
						 <entry> <para>
							Non-privileged users can use the role to configure the following interfaces:
						</para>
						 <itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									Interface 1		
								</para>

							</listitem>
							 <listitem>
								<para>	
									Interface 2
								</para>

							</listitem>	

						</itemizedlist>
						 </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>	

		 <para>
			Make items in a list grammatically parallel.
		</para>
		 <para>
			In the following example, the original three list items inconsistently use an infinitive verb form, and then a gerund, and then an imperative. In the improved example, all three list items consistently use an imperative statement. 
		</para>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> 
						 <itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									To obtain the file name of the default kernel with the <command>grubby</command> command: 
								</para>

							</listitem>
							 <listitem>
								<para>
									Finding the index number of the default kernel:
								</para>

							</listitem>
							 <listitem>
								<para>
									Use the <command>grubby</command> command to persistently change the default kernel:
								</para>

							</listitem>							

						</itemizedlist>
						 </entry>
						<entry> 
						 <itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									Obtain the file name of the default kernel with the <command>grubby</command> command:
								</para>

							</listitem>
							 <listitem>
								<para>
									Find the index number of the default kernel:
								</para>

							</listitem>
							 <listitem>
								<para>
									Use the <command>grubby</command> command to persistently change the default kernel:
								</para>

							</listitem>							

						</itemizedlist>
						 </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>

    </section>

    <section id="punc-in-lists"><title>Punctuation in Lists</title>
      <para>
        For each item in a list, start with either a complete sentence or a sentence fragment. 
      </para>
      <para>
        A <emphasis>complete sentence</emphasis> must include a subject and a verb.
        It conveys a complete thought, and can stand on its own. 
      </para>
      <para>
        For a list where all items are complete sentences, end each item with a period.
      </para>
      <para>
        Example:
      </para>
      <para>
        Which statement is true about deployments and deployment configurations?
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Deployments use replica sets, and deployment configurations use replication controllers.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Deployments use replication controllers, and deployment configurations use replica sets.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Deployments and deployment configurations both refer to the same thing.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Deployments use replica sets, and deployment configurations use stateful sets.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
        For a list where all items are sentence fragments, do not end the items with any punctuation.
      </para>
      <para>
        Example:
      </para>
      <para>
        Kubernetes networking provides the following capabilities:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Highly coupled container-to-container communications
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Pod-to-pod communications
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Pod-to-service communications
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            External-to-service communications
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
        Sometimes, list items might include some form of a verb, but if they do not also include a subject, then they are not capable of standing on their own. 
        Such items count as sentence fragments, and are not ended with any punctuation.
      </para>
      <para>
        Example:
      </para>
      <para>
        Common uses for jobs include the following tasks:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Initializing or migrating a database
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Calculating one-off metrics from information within the cluster
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Creating or restoring from a data backup
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
        Example:
      </para>
      <para>
        Consider the following settings when creating a route:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            An optional path, for path-based routes
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            A target port that the application listens to
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            An encryption strategy, depending on whether you need a secure or an insecure route
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
        For a list where the items start with sentence fragments, and any of those fragments are followed by a complete sentence, end each of the fragments and sentences with a period.
      </para>
      <para>
        Example:
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Identifier of the object schema version.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Schema identifier. In this example, the object conforms to the pod schema.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Name of the container inside a pod. 
            Container names are important for <command>oc</command> commands when a pod contains multiple containers.
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      <para>
        For information about punctuation in lead-in sentences that introduce a list, refer to <xref linkend="list-intro-punc"/>.
      </para>

    </section>
    </section>

		 <section id="Sentence_Structure-Noun_Stacking">
			<title>Noun Stacking</title>
			 <para>
				Modifier strings (modifier + noun + noun sentence format) and over-modified nouns (or <firstterm>noun stacks</firstterm>) are especially difficult to translate, particularly when several different combinations might make sense. Avoid a stack of more than three consecutive nouns.
			</para>

		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> Plastic tubing and syringe tips. </entry>
						 <entry> Plastic tubing and plastic syringe tips. </entry>

					</row>
					 <row>
						<entry> Set default printer configuration parameters for new users. Enter the maximum length of time that you want to keep the automatic synchronization address list updates in days and press Enter. </entry>
						 <entry> For new users, set the parameters to the default printer configuration. Enter the maximum length of time, in number of days, that you want to keep the address lists updated by automatic synchronization. Then, press Enter. </entry>

					</row>
					 <row>
						<entry> Standard system log management configuration rotates log files every week. </entry>
						 <entry> Standard configuration of system log management rotates log files every week. </entry>

					</row>					

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>
			 <para>
				Avoid a noun followed by a word that ends in <emphasis>-ing</emphasis>. Such a construction is difficult to translate.
			</para>

		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> The <command>nmap</command> utility scans privileged TCP ports looking for services. </entry>
						 <entry> The <command>nmap</command> utility scans privileged TCP ports to look for services. </entry>

					</row>
		

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>
  </section>

	</section>
	 <section id="genders">
		<title>Grammatical Genders</title>
		 <para>
			When using ambiguous pronouns such as "they" or "it", it is not always clear what they refer to. For languages that have different genders for nouns, it is important to know exactly what each pronoun refers to. For example, the word "it" can be translated in several different ways and might require other grammatical adjustments.
		</para>
		 <para>
			Further, an initialism such as <emphasis>RPM</emphasis> might refer to the package or to the package manager. In German, <emphasis>manager</emphasis> is a masculine noun, and so RPM requires the masculine article "der" when it refers to the RPM Package Manager. <emphasis>Package</emphasis> is a neuter noun, and requires the neuter article "das" when it refers to an RPM package.
		</para>
		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> Set the parameter XYZ to 1 in the configuration file <filename>/etc/config.conf</filename>. It configures the way the Gateway application handles incoming network traffic. </entry>
						 <entry> Set the XYZ parameter to 1 in the <filename>/etc/config.conf</filename> configuration file. This parameter configures how the Gateway application handles incoming network traffic. </entry>

					</row>
					 <row>
						<entry> The RPM is useful. </entry>
						 <entry> The RPM package is useful. <emphasis>OR</emphasis> The RPM Package Manager is useful. </entry>
	<!-- Does this sentence add any value? -->

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>

	</section>
	 <section id="Writing_Clearly_and_Succinctly-DocBook_Elements">
		<title>Using Markup Correctly</title>
    <para>
      If you use a markup language to write your content, make the most of the available tagging options.
      Many terms are not translatable, and should not be used as structural parts of a sentence.
    </para>
		 <para>
			Correctly marking up terms can help translators to understand the meaning of, and to identify, translatable and non-translatable terms.
		</para>


		 <table>
			<title></title>
			 <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
				<colspec colname="c1"></colspec>
				 <colspec colname="c2"></colspec>
				 <thead>
					<row>
						<entry> Example </entry>
						 <entry> Improvement </entry>

					</row>

				</thead>
				 <tbody>
					<row>
						<entry> In <filename>/some/path/</filename>, grep for XYZ. </entry>
						 <entry> In the <filename>/some/path/</filename> directory, use the <command>grep</command> command to search for "XYZ". </entry>

					</row>
					 <row>
						<entry> <option>param-2</option> contains a reference to the hostname return value from <systemitem>instance-2</systemitem>. </entry>
						 <entry> The <option>param-2</option> parameter contains a reference to the hostname return value from your second server instance, <systemitem>instance-2</systemitem>. </entry>

					</row>
					 <row>
						<entry> Troubleshoot Glance. </entry>
						 <entry> Troubleshoot the Glance image service. </entry>

					</row>
					 <row>
						<entry> Install the <package>maven-changelog-plugin</package>. </entry>
						 <entry> Install the <package>maven-changelog-plugin</package> package. </entry>

					</row>

				</tbody>

			</tgroup>

		</table>
    <note>
      <para>
        This guide does not try to cover the many ways that you can use markup languages to write content.
        Many online resources exist for these languages.
      </para>
    </note>

	</section>
	 <section id="Writing_Clearly_and_Succinctly-Code_Blocks">
		<title>Code Blocks</title>
		 <para>
			Avoid including commentary within the same box as command input or output. These comments might be confused with part of the output, and during translation might be accidentally overlooked and left in English.
		</para>
		 <para>
			For example, consider the word "Usage" in the following block:
		</para>

<screen>Usage: <command>rhevm-iso-uploader <replaceable>[options]</replaceable> list</command>
<command>rhevm-iso-uploader <replaceable>[options] </replaceable>upload <replaceable>[file1] [file2] [file3]</replaceable></command></screen>

      <para>
        For information about punctuation in lead-in sentences that introduce a code block, refer to <xref linkend="list-intro-punc"/>.
      </para>

	</section>
	 <section id="Writing_Clearly_and_Succinctly-Entities">
		<title>Entities</title>
		 <para>
			An entity is a primitive data type, which associates a string with either a unique alias (such as a user-specified name) or an SGML reserved word (such as #DEFAULT)<footnote> <para>
				<ulink url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SGML_entity" />
			</para>
			 </footnote>. Entities are called by reference, and take the form &amp;name; (both the ampersand and the semicolon are required).
		</para>
<!-- Is this information still useful and needed? -->
		 <para>
			Entities can be helpful in some cases, but they are more of a hindrance when used for terms that need translation. Translators must compare the string with the built document to determine what the entity stands for. These entities might even be overlooked and not be translated at all.
		</para>
		 <para>
			To avoid issues with incorrect or outdated entity values, problems with translation, and so on, only include the entities that are required to build your books. If you use Publican (<ulink url="https://fedorahosted.org/publican/" />) to create and maintain your documentation, it creates and populates the required entities with default values when you create a publication. Required entities vary by brand; only the following entities are required for a standard publication:
		</para>
		 <itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					PRODUCT
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					BOOKID
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					YEAR
				</para>

			</listitem>
			 <listitem>
				<para>
					HOLDER
				</para>

			</listitem>

		</itemizedlist>
		 <para>
			Do not include entities such as &amp;PRODNAME; or &amp;VERSION; and so on, or things like &amp;BIBLE; to represent "The King James Bible". To learn more about entities, refer to the relevant chapter in <ulink url="http://jfearn.fedorapeople.org/en-US/Publican/4.0/html/Users_Guide/index.html" />
		</para>

	</section>

</chapter>

