<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>
<chapter>
  <title>
    Minimalism
  </title>

  <para>
    &#34;Minimalism&#34;, in the context of technical writing, is
    writing less to write clearly.
  </para>

  <para>
    That definition, rewritten the <emphasis>wrong</emphasis> way:
  </para>

  <para>
    &#34;Minimalism&#34; is an artistic discipline that can appear in
    any medium, even technical writing. When writing technical
    documentation, you may want to use minimalism. You should write
    fewer words in order to reach your central point, but without the
    loss of useful or important information.
  </para>

  <para>
    The first version, while terse, is better. It is simple, it states
    exactly the information the author wants to convey, it leaves no
    room for questions. This is typical of minimalism.
  </para>

  <para>
    Advantages of minimalism are:
  </para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
	Writing fewer words provide fewer opportunities for you to
	make writing mistakes.
      </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>
	Readers are less likely to misinterpret the intent of a
	message when your writing is direct and concise.
      </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>
	Maintenance and updates are easier when there is less to
	maintain and update.
      </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>
	Translation of your writing to other languages is easier when
	the meaning of your writing is obvious.
      </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>
	Tech editing is faster when there are fewer words to review.
      </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
      <para>
	It is more efficient to write less to communicate more.
      </para>
    </listitem>

  </itemizedlist>

  <section id="minimalism_tutorial">
    <title>How to implement minimalism</title>

    <para>
      Humans tend to think verbosely, so minimalism does not usually
      occur in a first draft. That's expected, but during your
      self-edit, look for sentences that use idiomatic phrases,
      "filler" words, or that restate a point that has already been
      made, and rewrite them using fewer words.
    </para>

    <para>
      Here are some examples of how to use minimalism by
      rewriting verbose sentences&#58;
    </para>

    <variablelist>
      <title>Convert paragraphs to minimalism</title>

      <varlistentry>
	<term>
	  Bad &#40;21 words&#41;&#58;
	</term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    A static IP address should be set on the server in order
	    to log in to it remotely from the client.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
	<term>
	  Better &#40;12 words&#41;&#58;
	</term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Set a static IP address on the server to enable remote login.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      
      <varlistentry>
	<term>
	  Bad &#40;47 words&#41;&#58;
	</term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    The standard XYZ solution for the granularity concern
	    these concerns would be XYZ Bundle Repository (XBR), but
	    XBR failed to get traction in the market. Another example
	    of a popular software system that relies on XYZ but
	    choose to not rely on XBR is the Emacs editor.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>

      <varlistentry>
	<term>
	  Better &#40;20 words&#41;&#58;
	</term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <application>Emacs</application> is an XYZ-compliant
	    editor allowing developers to create and modify XYZ
	    bundles without installing XYZ Bundle Repository.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <para>
      Ideally, minimalism doesn't just shorten a sentence, but makes
      the point of the sentence clearer. It allows the reader to focus
      on what is important.
    </para>

  </section>

    <section id="minimalism_exercise">
      <title>Exercise</title>

      <para>
	Rewrite each paragraph, bearing minimalism in mind:
      </para>
      
      <orderedlist>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <!-- Do NOT correct this. It is intentionally wrong. -->
	    Click on the <guibutton>OK</guibutton> button to confirm
	    the action and close the dialogue box.
	  </para>
	</listitem>

	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <!-- Do NOT correct this. It is intentionally wrong. -->
	    Look through each menu item to familiarize yourself with
	    all the options available to you throughout the interface
	    before attempting to utilize the API so that you have some
	    idea of what functions users expect to have available to
	    them.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <!-- Do NOT correct this. It is intentionally wrong. -->
	    Click on the <guibutton>OX</guibutton> button to confirm
	    the action and close the dialogue box.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <!-- Do NOT correct this. It is intentionally wrong. -->
	    In the right panel, you should see that the
	    <guilabel>XYZ</guilabel> view will show that the most
	    recent task has been completed and is waiting for you to
	    continue. In order to verify this, click the
	    <guibutton>OK</guibutton> in the lower left corner of the
	    interface in your web browser. This will display a
	    verification message confirming that the test passed and
	    that it is safe for you to continue to the next phase of
	    the exercise.
	  </para>
	</listitem>

	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    <!-- Do NOT correct this. It is intentionally wrong. -->
	   As you will see later in this chapter, both the
	   <application>foo</application> and
	   <application>bar</application> applications work with a
	   pipeline concept, which is sequential. However, you may
	   want to use <application>foo</application> when it's
	   available, since it also has the ability to trigger an
	   exchange to multiple destinations simultaneously, utilizing
	   parallel processing where possible.
	 </para>
	</listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      
    </section>
  </chapter>
