<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
]>
<chapter>
  <title>
    Pronouns
  </title>

  <para>
    Pronouns are pointers to a noun. These are some common singular pronouns&#58;
  </para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
	you
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
	it
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
	this
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
	that
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>
    These are some common plural pronouns&#58;
  </para>

  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
	they
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
	these
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
	those
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para>
    In technical writing, pronouns are simplified because English
    doesn't assign gender to inorganic things.
  </para>

  <note>
    <para>
      If you are writing a use case and need to reference a fictional
      human, it's common to use generic terms, such as a job title
      instead of an arbitrary name, such as &#34;John&#34; or
      &#34;Jane&#34;, and the pronoun &#34;they&#34; instead of
      &#34;him&#34; or &#34;her&#34;.
    </para>
  </note>
  
  <section id="pronouns_tutorial">
    <title>How to use pronouns</title>

  <para>
    For pronouns to work as designed, they require two things&#58;
  </para>

  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
	The reader must know what noun the pronoun references.
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
	The tense of the pronoun and its noun and verb must match.
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>

  <para>
    Here are some examples&#58;
  </para>
  
    <formalpara>
      <title>Singular noun</title>
      
      <para>
	When referring back to a singular noun, use the pronoun
	<emphasis>it</emphasis>. For example&#58;
      </para>
    </formalpara>
      <para>
	The server is running RHEL 7, and it has 8 TB of storage.
      </para>	
    
    <formalpara>
      <title>Plural pronouns</title>

      <para>
	When referring back to a plural noun, use the pronoun
	<emphasis>they</emphasis>. For example&#58;
      </para>
    </formalpara>      
      <para>
	Desktop computers often get used for office tasks, but they
	can also be configured as servers for a small network.
      </para>

    <formalpara>
      <title>Possessive pronouns</title>
      
      <para>
	To indicate that a pronoun possesses something, use a
	the possessive form of the appropriate pronoun. For example&#58;
      </para>
    </formalpara>
    
      <para>
	Emacs is a text editor, but its real power is its LISP
	interpreter.
      </para>

      <para>
	The same applies for plural forms&#58;
      </para>

      <para>
	Open source programmers are brave to subject their code to the
	scrutiny of anyone who wants to look at it.
      </para>


    <formalpara>
      <title>Pronouns in context</title>
      
      <para>
	Sometimes a pronoun is used in a separate sentence from the
	one that establishes the noun it references. This relies on
	the reader to understand from context which noun the pronoun most
	likely refers to. 
      </para>
</formalpara>
      <para>
	Sometimes it is very obvious. In the phrase &#34;I like drinking coffee
	while I sit and type at my computer. Sometimes, I even dunk a
	doughnut into it,&#34; the reader knows from contextual clues
	that the writer means &#34;Sometimes, I even dunk a doughnut
	into my coffee&#34; and not &#34;Sometimes, I even dunk a
	doughnut into my computer.&#34;
      </para>

      <para>
	Sometimes it is less obvious. In the phrase &#34;The foo
	command is working to replace the bar command. It is installed
	by default, and it has a bug in it that erases all of your
	data permanently, so must not be used,&#34; the reader cannot
	know definitively which command erases all of their data and
	which command is safe. Sometimes, using a pronoun is not as
	effective as being explicit.
      </para>
    

    <formalpara>
      <title>Verify your pronouns</title>

      <para>
	To verify that a pronoun makes sense, reread a sentence or
	paragraph, replacing the pronoun you chose with the subject&#58;
	For example&#58;
      </para>
    </formalpara>    
      <para>
	Desktop computers often get used for office tasks, but desktop
	computers can also be configured as servers for a small
	network.
      </para>

      <para>
	If it still says what you meant to say, then you have placed
	the pronoun in the correct place. If it does not make sense,
	or if it impossible to read back with its subject replaced
	because there is no indication of what the correct subject is,
	then the pronoun has not been used correctly.
      </para>

  </section>

  <section id="pronouns_exercise">
    <title>Exercise</title>

    <para>
      Correct these pronouns as needed&#58;
    </para>

    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  The systems administrators imaged the computers so that
	  its host names followed a logical naming scheme.
	</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Return the laptop to the store and get refunded for them.
	</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
	<para>
	  Okular is the best PDF viewer on the market. Admittedly,
	  it's not the best format for digital releases compared to
	  EPUB, but it's great for printing.
	</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
	<para>
	  The systems administrators imaged each computer so that
	  its host name followed a logical naming scheme.
	</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
      
  </section>
</chapter>
